[CROWD MURMURING]
[人群骚动]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
DAVID MALAN: All right, this is CS50's Introduction
大卫·马兰：好的 这是CS50的介绍
to Programming with Python.
用Python编程
My name is David Malan, and this is our week on File I/O, Input and Output
我的名字是David Malan 这是我们关于文件I/O、输入和输出的一周
of files.
的文件
So up until now, most every program we've written just
到目前为止 我们写的大多数程序
stores all the information that it collects in memory--
将收集到的所有信息存储在内存中--
that is, in variables or inside of the program itself, a downside of which
也就是说 在变量或程序本身内部
is that, as soon as the program exits, anything you typed in,
一旦程序退出 你输入的任何东西
anything that you did with that program is lost.
你用那个程序做的一切都将丢失
Now, with files, of course, on your Mac or PC, you can hang on to information
现在 当然 有了文件 在你的Mac或PC上 你可以保留信息
long term.
长期.
And File I/O within the context of programming
以及编程环境中的文件I/O
is all about writing code that can read from, that is load information
都是关于编写可以读取的代码 即加载信息
from, or write to, that is save information to, files themselves.
从或写入 也就是将信息保存到文件本身
So let's see if we can't transition then from only
所以让我们看看我们是否能从只有
using memory and variables and the like to actually writing
使用内存和变量等来实际写入
code that saves some files for us and, therefore, data persistently.
代码 为我们保存一些文件 因此 数据持久
Well, to do this, let me propose that we first consider a familiar data
为了做到这一点 我建议我们首先考虑一个熟悉的数据
structure, a familiar type of variable that we've seen before, that of a list.
结构 一种我们以前见过的熟悉的变量类型 即列表
And using lists, we've been able to store more than one piece
使用列表 我们可以存储多个片段
of information in the past.
过去的信息
Using one variable, we typically store one value.
使用一个变量 我们通常存储一个值
But if that variable is a list, we can store multiple values.
但是如果这个变量是一个列表 我们可以存储多个值
Unfortunately, lists are stored in the computer's memory.
不幸的是 列表存储在计算机的内存中
And so once your program exits, even the contents of those disappear.
所以一旦你的程序退出 甚至那些内容也会消失
But let's at least give ourselves a starting point.
但我们至少要给自己一个起点
So I'm over here in VS Code.
所以我在VS Code这里
And I'm going to go ahead and create a simple program using
接下来我将创建一个简单的程序
code of names.py, a program that just collects people's names,
names.py的代码 一个只收集人名的程序
students' names, if you will.
学生的名字 如果你愿意
And I'm going to do it super simply initially
一开始我会非常简单地
in a manner consistent with what we've done in the past to get user input
以一种与我们过去所做的一致的方式来获取用户输入
and print it back out.
再打印出来
I'm going to say something like this, name equals input, quote/unquote,
我要说的是 名字等于输入 引号/不引号
what's your name?
你叫什么名字？
Thereby storing in a variable called name
从而将存储在一个名为name的变量中
the return value of input, as always.
输入的返回值 一如既往
And as always, I'm going to go ahead and very simply
像往常一样 我将继续非常简单地
print out a nice f string that says, hello, comma,
打印出一个漂亮的f字符串 它说 你好 逗号
and then, in curly braces, name to print out Hello, David, hello, world,
然后 用大括号把名字打印出来你好 大卫 你好 世界
whoever happens to be using the program.
不管是谁碰巧在使用这个程序
Let me go ahead and run this just to remind myself what I should expect.
让我继续运行这篇文章 只是为了提醒自己应该期待什么
And if I run python of names.py and hit Enter, type in my name like David,
如果我运行名为names.py的python并按Enter键 像David一样输入我的名字
of course, I now see Hello, comma, David.
当然 我现在看到的是你好 逗号 大卫
Suppose, though, that we wanted to add support not just for one name,
但是 假设我们想要添加对一个名称的支持
but multiple names-- maybe three names for the sake of discussion
但有多个名字--为了便于讨论 可能有三个名字
so that we can begin to accumulate some amount of information
这样我们就可以开始积累一些信息
in the program, such that it's really going
在这个项目中 所以它真的是
to be a downside if we keep throwing it away once the program exits.
一旦程序退出 如果我们继续扔掉它 那将是一个不利的方面
Well, let me go back into names.py up here at top.
好吧 让我再说一遍名字 最上面的那个
Let me proactively give myself a variable, this time called names,
让我主动地给自己一个变量 这一次叫做名字
plural.
复数
And set it equal to an empty list.
并将其设置为等于空列表
Recall that the square bracket notation, especially if nothing's inside of it,
回想一下方括号符号 特别是如果里面什么都没有的话
just means, give me an empty list that we can add things to over time.
我的意思是 给我一张空的清单 我们可以随着时间的推移添加一些东西
Well, what do we want to add to it?
那么 我们还想补充些什么呢？
Well, let's add three names, each from the user.
好吧 让我们添加三个名字 每个名字都来自用户
And let me say something like this, for underscore in range of 3,
让我这样说 为了在3的范围内下划线
let me go ahead and prompt the user with the input function
让我继续并使用输入功能提示用户
and getting their name in this variable.
并将他们的名字放在这个变量中
And then using list syntax, I can say, names.append name to that list.
然后使用列表语法 我可以说 姓名 将姓名添加到该列表中
And now I have, in that list, that given name--
现在 在这个名单上 我有了这个名字--
1, 2, 3 of them.
1个、2个、3个
Other points to note is, I could use a variable here,
另外需要注意的是 我可以在这里使用一个变量
like i, which is conventional.
像我一样 这是传统的
But if I'm not actually using i explicitly on any subsequent lines,
但如果我实际上没有在任何后续行中显式使用i
I might as well just use underscore, which is a Pythonic convention.
我不妨使用下划线 这是一种毕多德式的惯例
And actually, if I want to clean this up a little bit right now,
实际上 如果我现在想把这个整理一下
notice that my name variable doesn't really
注意我的name变量
need to exist because I'm assigning it a value
因为我给它赋值
and then immediately appending it.
然后立即添加它
Well, I could tighten this up further by just getting rid of that variable
我可以通过去掉这个变量来进一步简化
altogether and just appending immediately the return value of input.
并立即追加input的返回值
I think we could go both ways in terms of design here.
我认为我们可以在设计方面走两条路
On the one hand, it's a pretty short line, and it's readable.
一方面 这是一个相当短的行 它的可读性
On the other hand, if I were to eventually change this phrase
另一方面 如果我最终要改变这个短语
to be not what's your name but something longer,
不是你的名字而是更长的
we might want to break it out again into two lines.
我们可能想把它再分成两行
But for now, I think it's pretty readable.
但现在 我认为它是相当可读的
Now later in the program, let's just go ahead and print out those same names,
在程序的后面 让我们把这些名字打印出来
but let's sort them alphabetically so that it makes sense
但我们先把它们按字母顺序排序
to be gathering them all together, then sorting them, and printing them.
把它们收集起来 然后分类 打印出来
So how can I do that?
那我怎么做
Well, in Python, the simplest way to sort a list in a loop
在Python中 在循环中对列表进行排序的最简单方法
is probably to do something like this.
就是做这样的事
For name in names--
因为名字中的名字
but wait.
肯等待
Let's sort the names first.
我们先把名字排序
Recall that there's a function called sorted
回想一下 有一个函数叫做sorted
which will return a sorted version of that list.
这将返回该列表的排序版本
Now let's go ahead and print out an f string that says, again, hello,
现在让我们继续 打印出一个f字符串 再次 你好
bracket, name, close quotes.
方括号、名称、右引号
All right, let me go ahead and run this.
好吧 让我继续运行这个
So Python of names.py, and let me go ahead
所以names.py的Python 让我继续
and type in a few names this time.
这次输入几个名字
How about Hermione?
赫敏怎么样？
How about Harry?
哈利怎么样？
How about Ron?
罗恩呢
And notice that they're not quite in alphabetical order.
注意它们不是按字母顺序排列的
But when I hit Enter and that loop kicks in,
但当我按下回车键 循环开始时
it's going to print out, hello, Harry, hello, Hermione, hello,
它会打印出来 你好 哈利 你好 赫敏 你好
Ron, in sorted order.
罗恩 按顺序排列
But of course, now, if I run this program again, all of the names
当然 如果我再运行一次这个程序
are lost.
迷路了是
And if this is a bigger program than this,
如果这是一个比这更大的项目
that might actually be pretty painful to have
可能会很痛苦
to re-input the same information again, and again, and again.
一次又一次地重复输入相同的信息
Wouldn't it be nice, like most any program today
这不是很好吗 就像今天的大多数节目一样
on a phone, or a laptop, or desktop, or cloud
在手机、笔记本电脑、台式机或云上
to be able to save this information somehow instead?
才能以某种方式保存这些信息？
And that's where File I/O comes in.
这就是文件I/O的用武之地
And that's where files come in.
这就是文件的用武之地
They are a way of storing information persistently on your own phone, or Mac,
它们是一种在你自己的手机或Mac上持久存储信息的方式
or PC, or some cloud server's disk so that they're there when you
或者PC 或者某个云服务器的磁盘 这样当您
come back and run the program again.
请回来再次运行该程序
So how can we go about saving all three of these names on in a file as opposed
那么我们如何才能将这三个名字都保存在一个文件中 而不是
to having to type them again and again?
不得不一次又一次地打字？
Let me go ahead and simplify this file and, again,
让我继续简化这个文件 再一次
give myself just a single variable called name,
只给我自己一个名为name的变量
and set the return value of input equal to that variable.
并将输入的返回值设置为等于该变量
So what's your name, as before, quote/unquote.
那么你的名字是什么 和以前一样 引用/不引用
And now let me go ahead, and let me do something more with this value.
现在让我继续 让我用这个值做一些更多的事情
Instead of just adding it to a list or printing it immediately out,
而不是简单地将其添加到列表或立即打印出来
let's save the value of the person's name
让我们保存人名的值
that's just been typed in to a file.
刚刚被输入到一个文件中
Well, how do we go about doing that?
那么 我们该怎么做呢？
Well, in Python, there's this function called open whose purpose in life
在Python中 有一个名为OPEN的函数 它的用途是
is to do just that, to open a file, but to open it up programmatically
就是这样做 打开一个文件 但要以编程的方式打开它
so that you, the programmer, can actually read information from it
这样 作为程序员 您就可以真正从其中读取信息
or write information to it.
或向其写入信息
So open is like the programmer's equivalent of double clicking
所以打开就像程序员的双击
on an icon on your Mac or PC.
在Mac或PC上的图标上
But it's a programmer's technique because it's
但它是程序员的技术 因为它是
going to allow you to specify exactly what you want
允许您准确地指定您想要的内容
to read from or write to that file.
从该文件读取或写入该文件
Formally, it's documentation is here, and you'll
正式地说 它的文档在这里 您将
see that it's usage is relatively straightforward.
注意它的用法相对简单明了
It minimally just requires the name of the file that we want to open
它最低限度只需要我们要打开的文件的名称
and, optionally, how we want to open it.
以及我们希望如何打开它(可选)
So let me go back to VS Code here, and let me propose now that I do this.
所以让我回到VS代码这里 现在让我提议我这样做
I'm going to go ahead and call this function called open, passing
我将继续调用这个名为Open 传递的函数
in an argument for names.txt, which is the name of the file I would
在names.txt的参数中 这是我想要的文件名
like to store all of these names in.
我想把所有这些名字都存储在
I could call it anything I want.
我可以随心所欲地叫它
But because it's going to be just text, it's
但因为它将只是文本 所以
conventional to call it something.txt.
按惯例称它为某物.txt
But I'm also going to tell the open function
但我也要告诉Open函数
that I plan to write to this file.
我打算写进这份文件
So as a second argument to open, I'm going to put literally, quote/unquote,
作为第二个开场论点 我将从字面上说 引用/不引用
w, for Write, and that's going to tell open to open
W 用于写入 这将告诉Open to Open
the file in a way that's going to allow me to change the content.
该文件的方式将允许我更改内容
And better yet, if it doesn't even exist yet,
更好的是 如果它还不存在
it's going to create the file for me.
它将为我创建文件
Now, open returns what's called a file handle,
现在 OPEN返回所谓的文件句柄
a special value that allows me to access that file subsequently.
一个允许我随后访问该文件的特定值
So I'm going to go ahead and sign it equal to a variable like file.
所以我将继续 将它标记为等于一个变量 如FILE
And now I'm going to go ahead and, quite simply,
现在我要继续 非常简单地
write this person's name to that file.
把这个人的名字写到那个文件里
So I'm going to literally type file, which is the variable linking to that
所以我将按字面意思输入FILE 这是链接到它的变量
file, .write, which is a function otherwise known as a method that comes
文件.WRITE 这是一个函数 也称为
with open files that allows me to write that name to the file.
打开的文件允许我将该名称写入文件
And then lastly, I'm going to quite simply going
最后 我将非常简单地
to go ahead and say, file.close, which will close and effectively save
继续并说 文件.关闭 这将关闭并有效地保存
the file.
那份文件
So these three lines of code here are essentially the programmer's equivalent
所以这里的这三行代码基本上是程序员的等价物
to double clicking an icon on your Mac or PC,
要在Mac或PC上双击图标
making some changes in Microsoft Word or some other program,
在Microsoft Word或其他程序中进行一些更改
and going to File, Save.
然后依次转到文件、保存
We're doing that all in code with just these three lines here.
我们只用这三行代码来实现这一点
Well, let's see, now, how this works.
现在 让我们来看看这是如何运作的
Let me go ahead now and run python of names.py and Enter.
现在让我继续运行名为.py的python并按Enter键
Let's type in a name.
让我们输入一个名字
I'll type in Hermione, Enter.
我会输入赫敏 回车
All right, where did she end up?
好吧 她最后去了哪里？
Well, let me go ahead now and type code of names.txt,
好了 现在让我继续输入names.txt的代码
which is a file that happens now to exist
这是一个现在恰好存在的文件
because I opened it in write mode.
因为我是在写入模式下打开的
And if I open this in a tab, we'll see there is Hermione.
如果我在标签里打开这个 我们会看到赫敏
Well, let's go ahead and run names.py once more.
好了 让我们再运行一次names.py
I'm going to go ahead and run python of names.py, Enter, and this time,
我将继续运行names.py的python 回车 这一次
I'll type in Harry.
我来打哈里
Let me go ahead and run it one more time.
让我再运行一次
And this time, I'll type in Ron.
这一次 我将输入罗恩
And now let me go up to names.txt, where, hopefully, I'll see all three
现在让我转到names.txt 希望我能在那里看到所有三个
of them here.
他们在这里
But no.
但是没有
I've just actually seen Ron.
我刚真的看到了罗恩
What might explain what happened to Hermione and Harry,
怎么解释赫敏和哈利的遭遇
even though I'm pretty sure I ran the program three times,
即使我很确定我已经运行了三次程序
and I definitely wrote the code that writes their name to that file?
我确实写了把他们的名字写到那个文件里的代码？
What's going on here, do you think?
你觉得这是怎么回事？
AUDIENCE: I think because we're not appending them,
观众：我想是因为我们没有附加它们
we should append the names.
我们应该把名字加上去
Since we are writing directly, it is erasing the old content,
因为我们是直接写的 它是在删除旧的内容
and it is replacing with the last set of characters that we mentioned.
它将替换为我们提到的最后一组字符
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
大卫·马兰：没错
Unfortunately, quote/unquote w is a little dangerous.
不幸的是 引号/不引号w有点危险
Not only will it create the file for you,
它不仅会为您创建文件
it will also recreate the file for you every time you
它还将为您重新创建文件 每次您
open the file in that mode.
在该模式下打开文件
So if you open the file once and write Hermione,
所以如果你打开一次文件并写给赫敏
that worked just fine, as we saw.
正如我们所看到的 这一切运行得很好
But if you do it again for Harry, if you do it again for Ron,
但如果你再为哈利做一次 如果你再为罗恩做一次
the code is working.
代码起作用了
But each time, it's opening the file and recreating it with brand-new contents,
但每一次 它都会打开文件并用全新的内容重新创建
so we had one version with Hermione, and one version with Harry,
所以我们有赫敏的一个版本 和哈利的一个版本
and one final version with Ron.
和罗恩的最后一个版本
But ideally, I think we probably want to be appending,
但在理想情况下 我认为我们可能想要追加
as Vishal says, each of those names to the file,
正如维沙尔所说 这些名字中的每一个都被记录在文件中
not just clobbering-- that is, overwriting the file each time.
不仅仅是重写--也就是说 每次都覆盖文件
So how can I do this?
那么我该怎么做呢？
It's actually a relatively easy fix.
实际上 这是一个相对容易解决的问题
Let me go ahead and do this as follows.
让我继续按如下方式执行此操作
I'm going to first remove the old version of names.txt.
我将首先删除旧版本的names.txt
And now I'm going to change my code to do this.
现在我要更改我的代码来执行此操作
I'm going to change the w, quote/unquote, to just a,
我要将w 引用/非引用更改为一个
quote/unquote-- a for Append, which means to add to the bottom,
引用/不引用--a表示追加 意思是添加到底部
to the bottom, to the bottom, again and again.
到底部 到底部 一次又一次
Now let me go ahead and rerun python of names.py, Enter.
现在 让我继续并重新运行名为names.py的python 回车
I'll again start from scratch with Hermione
我将再次和赫敏从头开始
because I'm creating the file new.
因为我正在创建新的文件
Notice that if I now do code of names.txt, Enter, we do
请注意 如果我现在执行names.txt代码 回车 我们将执行
see that Hermione is back.
去看看赫敏回来了
So after removing the file, it did get recreated,
所以在删除文件后 它确实被重新创建了
even though I'm using append, which is good.
尽管我使用的是Append 这很好
But now let's see what happens when I go back to my terminal.
但现在让我们看看当我回到我的终端时会发生什么
And this time, I run python of names.py again--
这一次 我再次运行了名为.py的蟒蛇--
this time, typing in Harry.
这一次 输入哈里
And let me run it one more time--
让我再运行一次--
this time, typing in Ron.
这一次 输入罗恩
So hopefully, this time, in that second tab, names.txt,
所以希望这一次 在第二个选项卡中 names.txt
I should now see all three of them.
我现在应该看到他们三个人
But, but, but, but this doesn't look ideal.
但是 但是这看起来并不理想
What have I clearly done wrong?
我到底做错了什么？
Something tells me, even though all three names are there,
我有种感觉 尽管三个名字都在那里
it's not going to be easy to read those back unless you
除非你能把它们读回来 否则读起来不会很容易
know where each name ends and begins.
知道每个名字的结尾和开头
AUDIENCE: The English format is not correct.
观众：英文格式不正确
The English format is not correct.
英文格式不正确
It's incorrect.
这是不正确的
It's concatenating them.
它将它们连接在一起
DAVID MALAN: It is.
大卫·马兰：是的
Well, it appears to be concatenating.
嗯 它似乎是串联在一起的
But technically speaking, it's just appending to the file--
但从技术上讲 它只是添加到文件中--
first Hermione, then Harry, then Ron.
先是赫敏 然后是哈里 然后是罗恩
It has the effect of combining them back to back,
它的效果是将它们背靠背地结合在一起
but it's not concatenating, per se.
但就本质而言 它不是串联的
It really is just appending.
这真的只是一种附加
Let's go to another hand here.
让我们转到另一只手
What really have I done wrong?
我到底做错了什么？
Or equivalently, how might I fix?
或者说 我该如何修复呢？
It would be nice if there were some kind of gaps between each of the names,
如果每个名字之间都有一些空隙就好了
so we could read them more cleanly.
这样我们就能读得更清楚了
AUDIENCE: Hello.
观众：你好
We should add a new line before we write new name.
在写新名字之前 我们应该加一行
DAVID MALAN: Good.
大卫·马兰：很好
We want to add a new line ourselves.
我们想自己增加一条新线路
So whereas print by default, recall, always outputs, automatically,
因此 尽管默认打印、调用、总是自动输出
a line ending of backslash n.
以反斜杠n结尾的一行
Unless we override it with the named parameter called end,
除非我们用名为end的命名参数覆盖它
write does not do that.
WRITE不能做到这一点
Write takes you literally.
WRITE从字面上理解你
And if you say write Hermione, that's it.
如果你说写给赫敏 那就完了
You're getting the H through the e.
你得到的是通过e的H
If you say, write Harry, you get the H through the y.
如果你说 写哈里 你得到的H通过y
You don't get any extra new lines automatically.
您不会自动获得任何额外的新行
So if you want to have a new line at the end of each of these names,
所以如果你想在每个名字的末尾加上一行
we've got to do that manually.
我们必须手动完成
So let me, again, close names.txt, and let me remove the current file.
因此 让我再次关闭names.txt 并删除当前文件
And let me go back up to my code here.
让我回到我的代码上来
And I can fix this in any number of ways,
我可以用很多方法来解决这个问题
but I'm just going to go ahead and do this.
但我要继续做这件事
I'm going to write out an f string that contains name and backslash
我要写出一个包含名称和反斜杠的f字符串
n at the end.
N在末尾
We could do this in different ways.
我们可以用不同的方式来做这件事
We could manually print just the new line or some other technique,
我们可以手动打印新行或其他一些技术
but I'm going to go ahead and use my f strings, as I'm in the habit of doing,
但我会继续使用我的f弦 就像我习惯做的那样
and just print the name and the new line all at once.
只需同时打印名称和新行即可
I'm going to go ahead now and down to my terminal window, run python of names.py
现在 我将继续向下移动到我的终端窗口 运行names.py的python
again, Enter.
再次输入
We'll type in Hermione.
我们将输入赫敏
I'm going to run it again, type in Harry.
我要再运行一次 输入Harry
I'm going to type it again and this time, Ron.
我要再打一次 这次是罗恩
Now I'm going to run code of names.txt and open that file.
现在 我将运行names.txt代码并打开该文件
And now it looks like the file is a bit cleaner.
现在 文件看起来更干净了
Indeed, I have each of the name on its own line
事实上 我把每一个名字都写在自己的行上
as well as a line ending, which ensures that we can separate one
以及一个行尾 这确保了我们可以分开一个
from the other.
从另一个方面
Now, if I were writing code, I bet I could parse, that is, read
现在 如果我在编写代码 我打赌我可以解析 也就是读取
the previous file by looking at differences
通过查看差异来查看前一个文件
between lowercase and uppercase letters.
在小写字母和大写字母之间
But that's going to get messy quickly.
但这很快就会变得一团糟
Generally speaking, when storing data long-term in a file,
一般来说 当数据长期存储在文件中时
you should probably do it somehow cleanly, like doing one name at a time.
你可能应该以某种方式干净利落地做这件事 就像一次做一个名字
Well, let's now go back, and I'll propose
好吧 我们现在回去吧 我会向你求婚
that this code is now working correctly, but we
这段代码现在工作正常 但我们
can design it a little bit better.
可以把它设计得更好一点
It turns out that it's all too easy when writing code to sometimes forget
事实证明 在编写代码时 有时很容易忘记
to close files.
关闭文件
And sometimes, this isn't necessarily a big deal.
有时 这不一定是什么大事
But sometimes, it can create problems.
但有时 它也会带来问题
Files could get corrupted or accidentally deleted or the like,
文件可能被破坏或意外删除等
depending on what happens in your code.
这取决于代码中发生的情况
So it turns out that you don't strictly need to call close on the file yourself
因此 严格来说 您并不需要亲自调用Close来关闭文件
if you take another approach instead.
如果你采取另一种方法
More Pythonic when manipulating files is to do this,
当操纵文件时 更像是在做这件事
to introduce this other keyword called, quite simply,
要介绍另一个关键词 非常简单
with that allows you to specify that, in this context,
允许您在此上下文中指定
I want you to open and automatically close some file.
我要你打开并自动关闭一些文件
So how do we use with?
那么 我们如何使用呢？
It simply looks like this.
它看起来就像这样
Let me go back to my code here.
让我在这里回到我的代码
I've gotten rid of the close line.
我已经摆脱了封闭线
And I'm now just going to say this instead.
现在我只想这么说
Instead of saying, file equals open, I'm going
我不会说 档案等于打开 而是
to say, with open, then the same arguments as before,
要说 开放 然后像以前一样的论点
and somewhat curiously, I'm going to put the variable at the end of the line.
有点奇怪的是 我要把变量放在代码行的末尾
Why?
为什么？
That's just the way this is done.
这就是做这件事的方式
You say, with, you call the function in question,
你说 用 你调用有问题的函数
and then you say as and specify the name of the variable that should
然后输入As并指定变量的名称
be assigned the return value of open.
赋值为OPEN的返回值
Then I'm going to go ahead and indent the line underneath so
然后我将继续并缩进下面的线
that the line of code that's writing the name
写这个名字的那行代码
is now in the context of this with statement, which just ensures that,
现在是在这个With语句的上下文中 它只是确保
automatically, if I had more code in this file
自动地 如果我在这个文件中有更多的代码
down below no longer indented, the file would be automatically closed
向下不再缩进 文件将自动关闭
as soon as line 4 is done executing.
执行完第4行后立即执行
So it doesn't change what has just happened,
所以它不会改变刚刚发生的事情
but it does automate the process of at least closing things for us
但它确实自动化了至少为我们关闭东西的过程
just to ensure I don't forget and so that something doesn't go wrong.
只是为了确保我不会忘记 这样就不会出什么差错
But suppose, now, that I wanted to read these names from the file.
但是现在 假设我想要从文件中读取这些名字
All I've done thus far is write code that writes names to the file.
到目前为止 我所做的只是编写将名称写入文件的代码
But let's assume, now, that we have all of these names in the file.
但现在 让我们假设我们在文件中有所有这些名字
And heck, let's go ahead and add one more.
见鬼 让我们继续 再加一个
Let me go ahead and run this one more time-- python of names.py.
接下来让我再运行一次--python of names.py
And let's add in Draco to the mix.
让我们把德拉科加入到这个组合中
So now that we have all four of these names here,
所以现在我们有了这四个名字
how might we want to read them back?
我们可能想要怎么把它们读回来？
Well, let me propose that we go into names.py now,
好吧 让我提议我们现在进入name.py
or we could create another program altogether.
或者我们可以完全创建另一个项目
But I'm going to keep reusing the same name just to keep us focused on this.
但我会继续重复使用同一个名字 只是为了让我们专注于这个问题
And now I'm going to write code that reads an existing file with Hermione,
现在 我将编写代码 用Hermione读取现有文件
Harry, Ron, and Draco together.
哈利、罗恩和德拉科在一起
And how do I do this?
我该怎么做呢？
Well, it's similar in spirit.
嗯 它在精神上是相似的
I'm going to start this time with with open,
这一次 我将从Open开始
and then the first argument is going to be the name of the file
然后第一个参数将是文件的名称
that I want to open, as before.
我想打开它 就像以前一样
And I'm going to open it, this time, in read mode-- quote/unquote, r.
我将打开它 这一次 在读模式下--引用/不引用 r
And to read a file just means to load it, not to save it.
而读取文件只意味着加载它 而不是保存它
And I'm going to name the return value file.
我将为返回值文件命名
And now I'm going to do this.
现在我要这么做了
And there's a number of ways I can do this,
我有很多方法可以做到这一点
but one way to read all of the lines from the file at once would be this.
但是 一次从文件中读取所有行的一种方法是这样的
Let me declare a variable called lines.
让我声明一个名为LINES的变量
Let me access that file and call a function or a method that
让我访问该文件并调用一个函数或方法
comes with it called readlines.
它附带了一种叫做Readline的东西
So if you read the documentation on File I/O in Python,
因此 如果您阅读了有关文件I/O的文档
you'll see that open files come with a special method whose purpose in life
你会看到打开文件有一种特殊的方法 它在生活中的目的是
is to read all the lines from the file and return them to me as a list.
就是读取文件中的所有行并将它们作为列表返回给我
So what this line 2 is doing is it's reading all of the lines
这行2所做的就是读取所有行
from that file, storing them in a variable called lines.
将它们存储在一个名为LINES的变量中
Now, suppose I want to iterate over all of those lines
现在 假设我想遍历所有这些行
and print out each of those names.
并打印出每一个名字
For line in lines, this is just a standard for loop in Python.
对于每行中的行 这只是Python中循环的标准
Lines as a list.
作为一个列表的行
Line is the variable that will be automatically set
Line是将自动设置的变量
to each of those lines.
每一条线路
Let me go ahead and print out something like, oh, hello, comma,
让我继续打印出来 哦 你好 逗号
and then I'll print out the line itself.
然后我会把这行打印出来
All right, so let me go to my terminal window, run python of names.py now--
好的 现在让我打开终端窗口 运行names.py的python--
I have not deleted names.txt, so it still contains all four
我没有删除names.txt 所以它仍然包含所有四个
of those names-- and hit Enter, and OK, it's not bad,
然后按回车键 这还不错
but it's a little ugly here.
但这里有点难看
What's going on?
怎么回事？
When I ran names.py, it's saying Hello to Hermione, to Harry, to Ron,
当我运行names.py时 它在说你好 赫敏 哈利 罗恩
to Draco.
德拉科
But there's these gaps now between the lines.
但现在这两条线之间有了差距
What explains that symptom?
怎么解释这种症状？
If nothing else, it just looks ugly.
如果没有别的 它只是看起来很丑
AUDIENCE: It happens because in the text file,
观众：这是因为在文本文件中
we have new line symbols in between those names,
在这些名字之间有了新的线符号
and the print always adds another new line at the end.
打印总是在末尾添加另一个新行
So you use the same symbol twice.
所以你用同样的符号两次
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
大卫·马兰：完美
And here's a good example of a bug, a mistake in a program.
这是一个很好的bug的例子 一个程序中的错误
But if you just think about those first principles,
但如果你想想这些基本原则
like, how do each of the lines of code work that I'm using?
比如我使用的每一行代码是如何工作的
You should be able to reason, exactly as Ripal there to say that, all right,
你应该能够推理 就像里帕尔说的那样 好吧
well, one of those new lines is coming from the file after each name.
那么 这些新行中的一行来自每个名称后面的文件
And then, of course, print, all of these weeks later,
然后 当然 印刷 所有这些周后
is still giving us for free that extra new line.
还在免费给我们额外的新产品
So there's a couple possible solutions.
所以有几个可能的解决方案
I could certainly do this, which we've done in the past,
我当然可以做到这一点 我们过去已经做到了
and pass in a named argument to print, like end="".
并传入一个命名参数来打印 比如end=""
And that's fine.
这也没什么
I would argue a little better than that might actually
我会说得更好一点
be to do this, to strip off of the end of the line the actual new line
要做到这一点 剥离线的末端
itself so that print is handling the printing of everything, the person's
所以打印机处理打印的一切 人的
name as well as the new line.
新的名字 新的路线
But you're just stripping off what is really just an implementation
但你只是剥离了真正的实现
detail in the file.
文件中的细节
We chose to use new lines in my text file to separate one name from another.
我们选择在我的文本文件中使用新的行来将一个名称与另一个名称分开
So arguably, it should be a little cleaner in terms of design
所以可以说 它在设计上应该更干净一点
to strip that off and then let print print out
把它剥下来然后让打印机打印出来
what is really just now a name.
什么才是真正的名字
But that's ultimately a design decision.
但这最终是一个设计决定
The effect is going to be exactly the same.
效果将是完全相同的
Well, if I'm going to open this file and read all the lines
好的 如果我要打开这个文件并阅读所有行
and then iterate over all of those lines and print them each out,
然后遍历所有这些行并将其打印出来
I could actually combine this into one thing
我可以把这些合并成一件事
because, right now, I'm doing twice as much work.
因为 现在 我做的工作是原来的两倍
I'm reading all of the lines, then I'm iterating over all of the lines just
我读了所有的行 然后迭代了所有的行
to print out each of them.
把它们都打印出来
Well, in Python, with files, you can actually do this.
在Python中 使用文件 您实际上可以做到这一点
I'm going to erase almost all of these lines
我要抹去几乎所有这些线条
now, keeping only with statement at top.
现在 只在顶部保持声明
And inside of this with statement, I'm going to say this, for line in file,
在这个With语句的内部 我要说的是 在文件中的行
go ahead and print out, quote/unquote, hello, comma, and then line.rstrip.
继续打印 引号/非引号 Hello 逗号 然后line e.rstri.
So I'm going to take the approach of stripping off the end of the line.
所以我要采取的方法是剥离这条线的末端
But notice how elegant this is, so to speak.
但请注意 可以说 这是多么优雅
I've opened the file in line 1.
我已经打开了第1行中的文件
And if I want to iterate over every line in the file,
如果我想遍历文件中的每一行
I don't have to very explicitly read all the lines,
我不需要非常明确地读完所有的台词
then iterate over all of the lines.
然后迭代所有行
I can combine this into one thought.
我可以把这些整合成一个想法
In Python, you can simply say, for line in file,
在Python中 您可以简单地说 对于文件中的行
and that's going to have the effect of giving you a for loop that iterates
这将产生如下效果：给出一个迭代的for循环
over every line in the file, one at a time, and on each iteration,
在文件中的每一行上 一次一行 在每次迭代中
updating the value of this variable line to be Hermione,
将该变量行的值更新为Hermione
then Harry, then Ron, then Draco.
然后是哈利 然后是罗恩 然后是德拉科
So this, again, is one of the appealing aspects of Python
因此 这也是Python吸引人的方面之一
is that it reads rather like English-- for line in file, print this.
它读起来很像英语--对于文件中的行 打印这个
It's a little more compact when written this way.
这样写的话会更紧凑一些
Well, what if, though, I don't want quite this behavior?
好吧 但是 如果我不想要这种行为呢？
Because notice now, if I run python of names.py, it's correct.
因为现在请注意 如果我运行names.py的python 它是正确的
I'm seeing each of the names and each of the hellos,
我看到了每个人的名字和每个人的问候
and there's no extra spaces in between.
而且中间没有额外的空间
But just to be difficult, I'd really like us to be sorting these hellos.
不过 说起来有点难度 我真的希望我们能把这些问候整理好
Really, I'd like to see Draco first, then Harry, then Hermione, then Ron,
真的 我想先见见德拉科 然后是哈利 然后是赫敏 然后是罗恩
no matter what order they appear in the file.
无论它们在文件中的出现顺序如何
So I could go in, of course, to the file and manually change the file.
当然 我可以进入文件并手动更改文件
But if that file is changing over time based
但如果该文件随着时间的推移而变化
on who is typing their name into the program,
关于谁在程序中输入他们的名字
that's not really a good solution.
这真的不是一个好的解决方案
In code, I should be able to load the file, no matter what it looks
在代码中 我应该能够加载文件 无论它看起来是什么样子
like, and just sort it all at once.
就像 然后一下子把它们分类好
Now, here is a reason to not do what I've just done.
现在 这里有一个不做我刚刚做的事情的理由
I can't iterate over each line in the file and print it out
我无法遍历文件中的每一行并将其打印出来
but sort everything in advance.
但要提前把所有东西都分类好
Logically, if I'm looking at each line one at a time and printing it out,
从逻辑上讲 如果我一次查看一行并打印出来
it's too late to sort.
现在分类已经太晚了
I really need to read all of the lines first without printing them,
我真的需要先阅读所有行 而不是打印它们
sort them, then print them.
对它们进行分类 然后打印出来
So we have to take a step back in order to add now this new feature.
因此 我们必须后退一步 现在才能添加这一新功能
So how can I do this?
那么我该怎么做呢？
Well, let me combine some ideas from before.
好吧 让我把以前的一些想法结合起来
Let me go ahead and start fresh with this.
让我继续下去 重新开始吧
Let me give myself a list called names, and assign it an empty list,
让我给自己一个名为名字的列表 并给它分配一个空列表
just so I have a variable in which to accumulate all of these lines.
这样我就有了一个变量 用来累加所有这些行
And now let me open the file with open, quote/unquote, names.txt.
现在让我打开文件 打开文件 引用/取消引用 名称.txt
And it turns out, I can tighten this up a little bit.
事实证明 我可以把这个收紧一点
It turns out, if you're opening a file to read it,
事实证明 如果你打开一个文件来阅读它
you don't need to specify, quote/unquote, r.
您不需要指定、引用/取消引用、r
That is the implicit default.
这就是隐含的默认情况
So you can tighten things up by just saying, open names.txt.
因此 您只需说一句 打开names.txt 就可以让事情变得更紧密
And you'll be able to read the file but not write it.
您将能够读取该文件 但不能写入它
I'm going to give myself a variable called file, as before.
和前面一样 我将给自己一个名为FILE的变量
I am going to iterate over the file in the same way, for line in file.
对于文件中的行 我将以相同的方式迭代文件
But instead of printing each line, I'm going to do this.
但我不是打印每一行 而是这样做
I'm going to take my names list and append to it.
我要把我的名单附加到名单上
And this is appending to a list in memory,
这是附加到内存中的列表中的
not appending to the file itself.
而不是附加到文件本身
I'm going to go ahead and append the current line,
我将继续添加当前行
but I'm going to strip off the new line at the end
不过 最后我要把新台词去掉
so that all I'm adding to this list is each of the students' names.
所以我要加到这张名单上的只有每个学生的名字
Now I can use that familiar technique from before.
现在我可以使用以前熟悉的技术了
Let me go outside of this with statement because now I've read the entire file,
让我跳过这个WITH语句 因为现在我已经阅读了整个文件
presumably.
大概是吧
So by the time I'm done with lines 4 and 5,
所以当我读完第4行和第5行时
again, and again, and again, for each line in the file,
一次又一次地 对于文件中的每一行
I'm done with the file.
我已经看完文件了
It can close.
它可以关闭
I now have all of the students' names in this list variable.
我现在将所有学生的名字都放在这个list变量中
Let me do this.
让我来做吧
For name in, not just names, but the sorted names,
对于输入的名称 不仅是名称 而且是已排序的名称
using our Python function sorted, which does just that, and do print,
使用我们的Python函数排序 它就是这样做的 并打印出来
quote/unquote, with an f string, hello, comma,
引号/非引号 带有f字符串 您好 逗号
and now I'll plug in bracket name.
现在我要输入括号名称
So now, what have I done?
那么现在 我做了什么？
I'm creating a list at the beginning, just
我从一开始就创建了一个列表 只是
so I have a place to gather my data.
所以我有一个地方来收集我的数据
I then, on lines 3 through 5, iterate over the file from top to bottom,
然后 在第3行到第5行 从上到下迭代文件
reading in each line, one at a time, stripping off the new line
逐行阅读 一次读一行 去掉新行
and adding just the student's name to this list.
只把这名学生的名字加到这个名单上
And the reason I'm doing that is so that on line 7,
我这么做的原因是为了在7号线上
I can sort all of those names, now that they're all in memory,
我可以对所有这些名字进行排序 因为它们都在内存中
and print them in order.
并按顺序打印出来
I need to load them all into memory before I can sort them.
我需要将它们全部加载到内存中 然后才能对它们进行排序
Otherwise, I'd be printing them out prematurely,
否则 我会过早地把它们打印出来
and Draco would end up last instead of first.
德拉科最终会成为最后一名 而不是第一名
So let me go ahead in my terminal window and run python of names.py
因此 让我继续在我的终端窗口中运行names.py
now, and hit Enter.
现在 然后按Enter键
And there we go.
这就对了
The same list of four hellos, but now they're sorted.
相同的四个问候列表 但现在它们被排序了
And this is a very common technique.
这是一种非常常见的技术
When dealing with files and information more
在处理文件和信息时更多
generally, if you want to change that data in some way, like sorting it,
通常 如果您想以某种方式更改数据 例如对其进行排序
creating some kind of variable at the top of your program, like a list,
在程序的顶部创建某种变量 比如列表
adding or appending information to it just to collect it in one place,
在其中添加或附加信息只是为了在一个地方收集信息
and then do something interesting with that collection, that list,
然后用这些收藏和清单做一些有趣的事情
is exactly what I've done here.
正是我在这里所做的
Now, I should note that if we just want to sort the file,
现在 我应该注意到 如果我们只想对文件进行排序
we can actually do this even more simply in Python, particularly
实际上 我们可以在Python中更简单地实现这一点 尤其是
by not bothering with this names list, nor the second for loop.
通过不麻烦这个名字列表 也不是第二个for循环
And let me go ahead and, instead, just do more simply this.
让我继续下去 取而代之的是 更简单地做这个
Let me go ahead and tell Python that we want the file
让我继续并告诉Python我们需要该文件
itself to be sorted using that same sorted function,
使用相同排序函数对其自身进行排序
but this time on the file itself.
但这一次是在文件本身
And then inside of that for loop, let's just go ahead and print
然后在for循环中 让我们继续打印
right away our hello, comma, followed by the line itself,
我们马上打招呼 逗号 后面跟着行本身
but still stripping off of the end of it any white space therein.
但仍然去掉了它的末端的任何空白
If we go ahead and run this same program now
如果我们现在继续运行同样的程序
with python of names.py and hit Enter, we get the same result.
使用名为.py的python并按Enter键 我们会得到相同的结果
But of course, it's a lot more compact.
但当然 它要紧凑得多
But for the sake of discussion, let's assume
但为了便于讨论 我们假设
that we do actually want to potentially make some changes to the data
我们确实希望潜在地对数据进行一些更改
as we iterate over it.
当我们迭代它的时候
So let me undo those changes, leave things as is.
因此 让我撤销这些更改 让事情保持原样
Whereby now, we'll continue to accumulate all of the names first
现在 我们将首先继续积累所有的名字
into a list, maybe do something to them, maybe forcing them
变成一份清单 也许会对他们做些什么 也许会强迫他们
to uppercase or lowercase or the like, and then sort and print out each item.
大写或小写等 然后分类并打印出每一项
Let me pause and see if there's any questions
让我暂停一下 看看有没有什么问题
now on File I/O reading or writing or now accumulating all of these values
现在关于文件I/O读取或写入 或者现在累加所有这些值
in some list.
在某个名单上
AUDIENCE: Hi.
观众：嗨
Is there a way to sort the files--
有没有办法对文件进行分类--
instead if you want it from alphabetically from A to Z,
相反 如果你想按字母从A到Z的顺序排列
is there a way to reverse it from Z to A.
有没有办法把它从Z变为A呢？
Is there a little extension that you can add to the end to do that?
有没有一个小的扩展 你可以添加到结尾来做到这一点？
Or would you have to create a new function?
或者 您需要创建一个新函数吗？
DAVID MALAN: If you wanted to reverse the contents of the file?
David Malan：如果您想要反转文件的内容？
AUDIENCE: Yeah, so if you, instead of sorting them from A to Z
观众：是的 所以如果你不是从A到Z对它们进行排序
in ascending order, if you wanted them in descending order,
按升序排列 如果你想要它们按降序排列
is there an extension for that?
有延期吗？
DAVID MALAN: There is, indeed.
大卫·马兰：确实有
And as always, the documentation is your friend.
一如既往 文档是您的朋友
So if the goal is to sort them, not in alphabetical order, which
因此 如果目标是对它们进行排序 而不是按字母顺序 那么
is the default, but maybe reverse alphabetical order,
是默认的 但可能会颠倒字母顺序
you can take a look, for instance, at the formal Python documentation there.
例如 您可以在那里查看正式的Python文档
And what you'll see is this summary.
你将看到的是这个总结
You'll see that the sorted function takes the first argument, generally
您将看到排序后的函数通常接受第一个参数
known as an iterable.
称为可迭代数
And something that's iterable means that you can iterate over it.
而一些可迭代的东西意味着你可以迭代它
That is you can loop over it one thing at a time.
这就是说 你可以一次循环做一件事
What the rest of this line here means is that you can specify a key, like,
此行的其余部分意思是您可以指定一个密钥 例如
how you want to sort it, but more on that later.
您希望如何对其进行排序 但稍后会详细介绍
But this last named parameter here is reverse.
但这里最后命名的参数是相反的
And by default, per the documentation, it's false.
默认情况下 根据文档 它是错误的
It will not be reversed by default. But if we change that to true,
默认情况下 它不会被撤销 但如果我们把它变成真的
I bet we can do that.
我打赌我们能做到
So let me go back to VS Code here and do just that.
因此 让我回到VS代码 并执行该操作
Let me go ahead and pass in a second argument
让我继续并传递第二个参数
to sorted in addition to this iterable, which is my names list--
要排序除了这个迭代 这是我的名字列表--
iterable, again, in the sense that it can be looped over.
同样 在循环的意义上 它是可迭代的
And let me pass in reverse=True, thereby overriding the default of false.
并让我反向传递=True 从而覆盖默认的False
Let me now run python of names.py.
现在让我运行名为.py的python
And now Ron's at the top, and Draco's at the bottom.
现在罗恩在顶端 德拉科在底端
So there, too, whenever you have a question like that moving forward,
所以 在那里 无论何时你有这样的问题
consider, what does the documentation say?
考虑一下 文档是怎么说的？
And see if there's a germ of an idea there because, odds are,
看看是否有一个萌芽的想法 因为 可能性很大
if you have some problem, odds are, some programmer
如果你有什么问题 很可能是某个程序员
before you has had the same question.
之前你也有过同样的问题
Other thoughts?
还有其他想法吗？
AUDIENCE: Can we limit the number or numbers of names?
观众：我们能限制名字的数量吗？
And the second question, can we find a specific name in list?
第二个问题 我们能在名单中找到一个具体的名字吗？
DAVID MALAN: Really good question, can we
大卫·马兰：这个问题问得很好 我们可以吗？
limit the number of the names in the file?
是否限制文件中的名称数量？
And can we find a specific one?
我们能找到一个具体的吗？
We absolutely could.
我们绝对可以
If we were to write code, we could, for instance,
如果我们要写代码 我们可以 例如
open the file first, count how many lines are already there,
首先打开文件 数一数已经有多少行
and then if there's too many already, we could just
如果已经有太多了 我们可以
exit with sys.exit or some other message to indicate to the user
退出 并显示sys.exit或其他向用户指示的消息
that, sorry, the class is full.
那个 对不起 班上已经满了
As for finding someone specifically, absolutely.
至于具体地、绝对地找到一个人
You could imagine opening the file, iterating over it with a for loop
您可以想象打开文件 使用for循环迭代它
again and again and then adding a conditional.
一遍又一遍 然后添加一个条件
Like, if the current line equals equals Harry, then we found the chosen run.
比如 如果当前行等于Harry 那么我们就找到了所选的行号
And you can print something like that.
你可以打印一些类似的东西
So you can absolutely combine these ideas with previous ideas,
所以你完全可以把这些想法和以前的想法结合起来
like conditionals, to ask those same questions.
就像条件句一样 问同样的问题
How about one other question on File I/O?
关于文件I/O的另一个问题如何？
AUDIENCE: So I just thought about this function, like read all the lines.
观众：所以我就想到了这个功能 比如读完所有的台词
And it looks like it's separate all the lines
看起来像是把所有的线都分开了
by this special character, backslash.
这个特殊的字符 反斜杠
And but it looks like we don't need it character, and we always strip it.
但看起来我们不需要它的角色 我们总是剥离它
And it looks like some bad design or function.
它看起来像是一些糟糕的设计或功能
Why wouldn't we just strip it inside this function?
为什么我们不在这个函数中去掉它呢？
DAVID MALAN: A really good question.
大卫·马兰：这是一个非常好的问题
So we are, in my examples thus far, using rstrip
因此 在我到目前为止的示例中 我们使用的是rstrain
to strip from the end of the line all of this white space.
去掉行尾的所有空白处
You might not want to do that.
你可能不想这么做
In this case, I am stripping it away because I know that each of those lines
在本例中 我将去掉它 因为我知道每一行
isn't some generic line of text.
不是什么普通的文本行
Each line really represents a name that I have put there myself.
每一行实际上代表了我自己在那里放的一个名字
I'm using the new line just to separate one value from another.
我使用新行只是为了将一个值与另一个值分开
In other scenarios, you might very well want
在其他情况下 您可能非常希望
to keep that line ending because it's a very long series of text,
为了保持这一行的结尾 因为它是一系列非常长的文本
or a paragraph, or something like that, where you want
或一段 或类似的东西 在你想要的地方
to keep it distinct from the others.
以保持它与其他动物的区别
But it's just a convention.
但这只是一次会议
We have to use something, presumably, to separate one chunk of text
我们必须使用某种东西 大概是用来分隔一段文本
from another.
从另一个人那里
There are other functions in Python that will, in fact, handle the removal
实际上 在Python中还有其他函数可以处理删除操作
of that white space for you.
为你保留那片空白的空间
Readlines, though, does literally that, though.
不过 Readline确实做到了这一点
It reads all of the lines as is.
它按原样读取所有行
Well, allow me to turn our attention back to where we left off here,
好吧 请允许我把我们的注意力转回到我们在这里停止的地方
which is just names to propose that, with names.txt, we have an ability,
这只是名字来建议 有了names.txt 我们有能力
it seems, to store each of these names pretty straightforwardly.
似乎 将这些名字中的每一个都存储得相当简单
But what if we wanted to keep track of other information as well?
但是 如果我们还想跟踪其他信息 该怎么办？
Suppose that we wanted to store information,
假设我们想要存储信息
including a student's name and their house at Hogwarts,
包括一名学生的名字和他们在霍格沃茨的房子
be it Gryffindor, or Slytherin, or something else.
不管是格兰芬多 还是斯莱特林 还是别的什么
Well, where do we go about putting that?
那么 我们应该把它放在哪里呢？
Hermione lives in Gryffindor, so we could do something
赫敏住在格兰芬多 所以我们可以做点什么
like this in our text file.
在我们的文本文件中是这样的
Harry lives in Gryffindor, so we could do that.
哈里住在格兰芬多 所以我们可以去
Ron lives in Gryffindor,
罗恩住在格兰芬多 所以我们可以去
And Draco lives in Slytherin, so we could do that.
德拉科住在斯莱特林 所以我们可以这么做
But I worry here--
但我担心的是--
but I worry now that we're mixing apples and oranges, so to speak.
但我现在担心的是 可以说 我们是在混合苹果和橙子
Some lines are names.
有些行是名字
Some lines are houses.
有些线就是房子
So this probably isn't the best design, if only because it's confusing,
所以这可能不是最好的设计 如果只是因为它令人困惑
or it's ambiguous.
或者它是模棱两可的
So maybe what we could do is adopt a convention.
因此 也许我们可以做的是通过一项公约
And indeed, this is, in fact, what a lot of programmers do.
事实上 这是许多程序员都在做的事情
They change this file not to be names.txt, but instead, let
他们不将此文件更改为names.txt 而是让
me create a new file called names.csv.
我创建了一个名为names.csv的新文件
CSV stands for Comma-Separated Values.
CSV代表逗号分隔值
And it's a very common convention to store multiple pieces of information
存储多条信息是一种非常常见的约定
that are related in the same file.
它们在同一文件中相关
And so to do this, I'm going to separate each of these types of data,
因此 为了做到这一点 我将分离这些类型的数据
not with another new line, but simply with a comma.
不是用新的一行 而是简单地用逗号
I'm going to keep each student on their own line,
我会让每个学生保持在他们自己的线路上
but I'm going to separate the information about each student using
但我将使用以下工具来分离每个学生的信息
a comma instead.
用逗号代替
And so now we sort of have a two-dimensional file, if you will.
所以现在我们有了一个二维文件 如果你愿意的话
Row by row, we have our students.
一排接一排 我们有学生
But if you think of these commas as representing a column,
但如果你认为这些逗号代表一列
even though it's not perfectly straight because of the lengths of these names,
尽管由于这些名字的长度 它不是完全笔直的
it's a little jagged.
它有点参差不齐
You can think of these commas as representing a column.
您可以将这些逗号视为代表一列
And it turns out, these CSV files are very commonly
事实证明 这些CSV文件非常常见
used when you use something like Microsoft Excel, Apple Numbers,
当您使用Microsoft Excel、Apple Numbers、
or Google Spreadsheets, and you want to export the data to share
或Google电子表格 而您想要将数据导出以共享
with someone else as a CSV file.
与其他人作为CSV文件
Or conversely, if you want to import a CSV
或者相反 如果要导入CSV
file into your preferred spreadsheet software,
文件保存到您首选的电子表格软件中
like Excel, or Numbers, or Google Spreadsheets, you can do that as well.
像Excel、数字或谷歌电子表格一样 你也可以做到这一点
So CSV is a very common, very simple text format
CSV是一种非常常见、非常简单的文本格式
that just separates values with commas and different types of values,
这只是用逗号和不同类型的值来分隔值
ultimately, with new lines as well.
最终 也会有新的线路
Let me go ahead and run code of students.csv
让我继续运行Students.csv的代码
to create a brand-new file that's initially empty.
创建一个最初为空的全新文件
And we'll add to it those same names but also some other information as well.
我们将添加这些相同的名称 但也会添加一些其他信息
So if I now have this new file, students.csv, inside of which
因此 如果我现在有这个新文件 Students.csv 其中
is one column of names, so to speak, and one column of houses,
可以说是一列名字和一列房子
how do I go about changing my code to read not just those names but also
我如何更改我的代码 使其不仅读取这些名称 还读取
those names and houses so that they're not all on one line--
那些名字和房子 这样它们就不会都在一行上了--
we somehow have access to both type of value separately?
我们以某种方式可以分别获得这两种类型的价值？
Well, let me go ahead and create a new program here called students.py.
好的 让我们继续在这里创建一个名为Students.py的新程序
And in this program, let's go about reading,
在这个节目中 让我们开始阅读
not a text file, per se, but a specific type of text file, a CSV,
不是文本文件本身 而是特定类型的文本文件 CSV
a Comma-Separated Values file.
逗号分隔值文件
And to do this, I'm going to use similar code as before.
要做到这一点 我将使用与前面类似的代码
I'm going to say with open, quote/unquote, students.csv.
我将用开放的 引用/不引用的方式说 Students.csv
I'm not going to bother specifying, quote/unquote,
我不会费心具体说明 引用/不引用
r because, again, that's the default.
因为 同样 这是默认的
But I'm going to give myself a variable name of file.
但我将为自己指定一个变量名为FILE
And then in this file, I'm going to go ahead and do this.
然后在这个文件中 我将继续执行此操作
For line in file, as before, and now I have to be a bit clever here.
对于文件中的行 就像以前一样 现在我必须在这里有点聪明了
Let me go back to students.csv, looking at this file,
让我回到Students.csv 看看这份文件
and it seems that on my loop on each iteration,
似乎在我每次迭代的循环中
I'm going to get access to the whole line of text.
我要访问整行文本
I'm not going to automatically get access
我不会自动获得访问权限
to just Hermione or just Gryffindor.
只给赫敏或格兰芬多
Recall that the loop is going to give me each full line of text.
回想一下 循环将为我提供每一整行文本
So logically, what would you propose that we
所以从逻辑上讲 你会建议我们
do inside of a for loop that's reading a whole line of text at once,
在一次读取一整行文本的for循环中执行
but we now want to get access to the individual values,
但我们现在想要接触到个人价值
like Hermione and Gryffindor, Harry and Gryffindor?
就像赫敏和格兰芬多 哈利和格兰芬多？
How do we go about taking one line of text
我们该如何处理一行文本呢
and gaining access to those individual values, do you think?
并获得这些个人价值观 你认为呢？
Just instinctively, even if you're not sure what the name of the functions
只是本能地 即使您不确定函数的名称
would be.
那就是
AUDIENCE: You can access it as you would as if you were using a dictionary,
听众：你可以像使用词典一样访问它
like using a key and value.
就像使用键和值一样
DAVID MALAN: So ideally, we would access it using it a key and value.
David Malan：所以 理想情况下 我们会使用键和值来访问它
But at this point in the story, all we have is this loop,
但在故事的这一点上 我们所拥有的只有这个循环
and this loop is giving me one line of text that is the time.
这个循环给了我一行文字 那就是时间
I'm the programmer now.
我现在是程序员了
I have to solve this.
我必须解决这个问题
There is no dictionary yet in question.
目前还没有一本有问题的词典
How about another suggestion here?
这里的另一个建议如何？
AUDIENCE: So you can somehow split the two words based on the comma?
听众：所以你可以根据逗号把这两个词分开？
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, even if you're not quite
大卫·马兰：是的 即使你不是很
sure what function is going to do this, intuitively,
直观地说 哪个函数可以做到这一点
you want to take this whole line of text--
你想把这整行文字--
Hermione, comma, Gryffindor, Harry, comma, Gryffindor, and so forth--
赫敏、逗号、格兰芬多、哈利、逗号、格兰芬多等等--
and split that line into two pieces, if you will.
如果你愿意的话 把这条线分成两部分
And it turns out wonderfully, the function we'll use
事实证明 我们将使用的函数
is actually called split that can split on any characters,
实际上称为拆分 可以对任何字符进行拆分
but you can tell it what character to use.
但您可以告诉它使用什么字符
So I'm going to go back into students.py, and inside of this loop,
所以我将返回到Students.py 在这个循环中
I'm going to go ahead and do this.
我要继续做这件事
I'm going to take the current line.
我要坐现在这条线
I'm going to remove the white space at the end, as always, using rstrip here.
我将一如既往地删除结尾处的空格 在这里使用rstrain
And then whatever the result of that is, I'm
不管结果如何 我都会
going to now call split and, quote/unquote, comma.
现在 我们将调用Split 并引用/不引用逗号
So the split function or method comes with strings.
因此 Split函数或方法附带字符串
Strs in Python-- any str has this method built-in.
Python中的STR--任何字符串都内置了这个方法
And if you pass in an argument, like a comma, what this split function will do
如果您传入一个参数 如逗号 则此拆分函数将执行什么操作
is split that current string into 1, 2, 3, maybe more pieces by looking
通过查找将当前字符串分割成1、2、3 也许更多片段
for that character again and again.
一次又一次地为那个角色
Ultimately, split is going to return to us
最终 斯普利特会回到我们身边
a list of all of the individual parts to the left
左侧所有单独部件的列表
and to the right of those commas.
在这些逗号的右侧
So I can give myself a variable called row here.
所以我可以在这里给自己一个名为row的变量
And this is a common paradigm.
这是一个常见的范例
When you know you're iterating over a file, specifically a CSV,
当您知道您正在迭代一个文件 特别是CSV时
it's common to think of each line of it as being
通常认为它的每一行都是
a row and each of the values therein separated by commas as columns,
一行和其中的每个值以逗号分隔为列
so to speak.
可以这么说
So I'm going to deliberately name my variable row, just
所以我将故意将我的变量行命名为
to be consistent with that convention.
以符合这一惯例
And now what do I want to print?
现在我要打印什么呢？
Well, I'm going to go ahead and say this.
好吧 我要说的就是这个
Print, how about the following, an f string that starts with curly braces--
打印一个以大括号开头的f字符串 怎么样？
well, how do I get access to the first thing in that row?
那我怎么才能接触到那一排的第一件东西呢？
Well, the row is going to have how many parts?
好的 这一排有几个部分？
Two, because if I'm splitting on commas, and there's one comma per line,
第二 因为如果我用逗号拆分 每行有一个逗号
that's going to give me a left part and a right part,
这会给我一个左边的部分和一个右边的部分
like Hermione and Gryffindor, Harry and Gryffindor.
就像赫敏和格兰芬多 哈利和格兰芬多
When I have a list like row, how do I get access to individual values?
当我有一个像ROW这样的列表时 我如何访问各个值？
Well, I can do this.
好吧 我能做到的
I can say, row, bracket, 0.
我可以说 排 括号 0
And that's going to go to the first element of the list, which
这将进入列表的第一个元素 即
should hopefully be the student's name.
希望应该是这个学生的名字
Then after that, I'm going to say, is in,
然后 我要说的是 在那之后
and I'm going to have another curly brace here for row, bracket, 1.
我要在这里再加一个花括号 放在第一排的括号里
And then I'm going to close my whole quote.
然后我将结束我的整个引用
So it looks a little cryptic at first glance.
因此 乍一看 它看起来有点神秘
But most of this is just f string syntax with curly braces to plug in values.
但其中大部分只是f字符串语法 用大括号插入值
And what values am I plugging in?
我在灌输什么价值观？
Well, row, again, is a list, and it has two elements, presumably--
好吧 ROW 同样是一个列表 它有两个元素 大概是--
Hermione in one and Gryffindor in the other, and so forth.
赫敏在一个 格兰芬多在另一个 以此类推
So bracket 0 is the first element because, remember,
因此 括号0是第一个元素 因为 记住
we start indexing at 0 in Python.
在Python语言中 我们从0开始索引
And 1 is going to be the second element.
而1将是第二个元素
So let me go ahead and run this now and see what happens--
所以现在让我继续运行 看看会发生什么--
python of students.py, Enter.
Python of Students.py 请输入
And we see Hermione is in Gryffindor.
我们看到赫敏在格兰芬多
Harry's in Gryffindor.
哈利在格兰芬多
Ron is in Gryffindor.
罗恩在格兰芬多
And Draco is in Slytherin.
德拉科在斯莱特林
So we have now implemented our own code from scratch that actually parses,
因此 我们现在已经从头开始实现了我们自己的代码 它实际上可以解析
that is, reads and interprets a CSV file ultimately here.
也就是说 最终在这里读取和解释CSV文件
Now, let me pause to see if there's any questions.
现在 让我暂停一下 看看有没有什么问题
But we'll make this even easier to read in just a moment.
但我们稍后会让这篇文章更容易阅读
Any questions on what we've just done here by splitting by comma?
对我们刚才用逗号分隔所做的工作有什么问题吗？
AUDIENCE: So my question is, can we edit any line of code any time we want?
观众：所以我的问题是 我们可以随时编辑任何代码行吗？
Or the only option that we have is to append the lines?
或者我们唯一的选择就是添加这些行？
Or let's say, we want to, let's say, change Harry's house
或者比方说 我们想 比方说 改变哈利的房子
to Slytherin or some other house.
去斯莱特林或其他房子
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, a really good question.
大卫·马兰：是的 这是一个非常好的问题
What if you want to, in Python, change a line in the file and not just
如果您想要在Python语言中更改文件中的一行 而不仅仅是
append to the end?
追加到末尾吗？
You would have to implement that logic yourself.
你必须自己实现这一逻辑
So for instance, you could imagine now opening the file
例如 您可以想象现在打开文件
and reading all of the contents in, then maybe iterating over
然后阅读其中的所有内容 然后可能迭代
each of those lines.
每一行都是
And as soon as you see that the current name equals equals Harry,
一旦你看到现在的名字等于哈利
you could maybe change his house to Slytherin.
你也许可以把他的房子换成斯莱特林
And then it would be up to you, though, to write all of those changes
然而 接下来要由您来编写所有这些更改
back to the file.
回到文件上来
So in that case, you might want to, in simplest form,
因此 在这种情况下 您可能想要 以最简单的形式
read the file once and let it close.
阅读文件一次 然后让它关闭
Then open it again, but open for writing, and change the whole file.
然后再次打开它 但要打开以进行写入 并更改整个文件
It's not really possible or easy to go in and change just part of the file,
进入并只更改文件的一部分并不是真正可能或容易的
though you can do it.
虽然你能做到
It's easier to actually read the whole file, make your changes in memory,
更容易实际读取整个文件 在内存中进行更改
then write the whole file out.
然后把整个文件写出来
But for larger files where that might be quite slow,
但对于较大的文件 其速度可能会相当慢
you can be more clever than that.
你可以比这更聪明
Well, let me propose now that we clean this up a little bit because I actually
好吧 现在让我提议我们稍微清理一下 因为我实际上
think this is a little cryptic to read-- row, bracket, 0, row, bracket,
我觉得这读起来有点神秘--行 括号 0 行 括号
1-- it's not that well-written at the moment, I would say.
1--我想说 目前这本书写得不是很好
But it turns out that when you have a variable that's a list like row,
但事实证明 当你有一个像ROW这样的列表的变量时
you don't have to throw all of those variables into a list.
您不必将所有这些变量都放到一个列表中
You can actually unpack that whole sequence at once.
实际上 你可以一次解开整个序列
That is to say, if you know that a function like split returns a list,
也就是说 如果您知道像Split这样的函数返回一个列表
but you know in advance that it's going to return
但你事先知道它会回来的
two values in a list, the first and the second,
列表中的两个值 第一个和第二个
you don't have to throw them all into a variable that itself is a list.
您不必将它们全部放入本身就是一个列表的变量中
You can actually unpack them simultaneously into two variables,
你实际上可以同时把它们分解成两个变量
doing name, comma, house.
做名字 逗号 房子
So this is a nice Python technique to not only create, but assign,
因此 这是一种很好的Python技术 不仅可以创建 还可以分配
automatically, in parallel, two variables at once,
自动地 同时并行地 两个变量
rather than just one.
而不是只有一个
So this will have the effect of putting the name in the left, Hermione,
所以这将产生把名字放在左边的效果 赫敏
and it will have the effect of putting Gryffindor
它的效果就是把格兰芬多
the house in the right variable.
房子在右边的变数里
And we now no longer have a row.
我们现在不再有争吵了
We can now make our code a little more readable by now literally just saying
我们现在可以让我们的代码更具可读性 字面意思是
name down here and, for instance, house down here.
名字在这里 例如 房子在这里
So just a little more readable, even though, functionally, the code
所以只是可读性更好一点 尽管从功能上讲 代码
now is exactly the same.
现在的情况完全一样
All right, so this now works.
好了 现在这招起作用了
And I'll confirm as much by just running it once more-- python of students.py,
我将通过再次运行它来确认这一点--python of Students.py
Enter.
进来吧
And we see that the text is as intended.
我们看到 文本符合预期
But suppose, for the sake of discussion, that I'd
但为了便于讨论 假设我
like to sort this list of output.
我想对这份输出列表进行排序
I'd like to say hello, again, to Draco first, then hello to Harry,
我想再次向德拉科打个招呼 然后向哈里打招呼
then Hermione, then Ron.
然后是赫敏 然后是罗恩
How can I go about doing this?
我该如何着手做这件事呢？
Well, let's take some inspiration from the previous example, where
好的 让我们从前面的例子中获得一些启发 其中
we were only dealing with names and, instead, do it with these full phrases.
我们只处理名字 而不是用这些完整的短语
So and so is in house.
在公司内部也是如此
Well, let me go ahead and do this.
好吧 让我继续做这件事
I'm going to go ahead and start scratch and give myself a list called students,
我将继续从头开始 给自己列一份名为学生的名单
equal to an empty list, initially.
最初等于一个空列表
And then with open students.csv as file, I'm going to go ahead and say this--
然后以开放的Students.csv为文件 我将继续这样说--
for line in file.
用于文件中的行
And then below this, I'm going to do exactly as before-- name, comma,
然后在这个下面 我将一如既往地做--名字 逗号
house equals the current line, stripping off the white space at the end,
House等于当前行 去掉了结尾处的空白
splitting it on a comma--
用逗号把它分开--
so that's exact same as before.
所以这和以前完全一样
But this time, before I go about printing the sentence,
但这一次 在我开始打印句子之前
I'm going to store it temporarily in a list
我要把它暂时存储在一个列表中
so that I can accumulate all of these sentences and then sort them later.
这样我就可以积累所有这些句子 然后在以后对它们进行分类
So let me go ahead and do this.
所以让我继续做这件事
Students, which is my list, .append--
学生们 这是我的名单 追加--
let me append the actual sentence I want to show
让我附上我想要显示的实际句子
on the screen-- so another f string.
在屏幕上--也就是另一个f弦
So name is in house, just as before.
所以 名字就在家里 就像以前一样
But notice, I'm not printing that sentence.
但请注意 我不会打印这句话
I'm appending it to my list-- not a file, but to my list.
我将它添加到我的列表中--不是一个文件 而是我的列表
Why am I doing this?
我为什么要这么做？
Well, just because, as before, I want to do this.
嗯 只是因为 像以前一样 我想这么做
For student in the sorted students, I want
对于排序后的学生 我希望
to go ahead and print out students, like this.
把学生打印出来 就像这样
Well, let me go ahead and run python of students.py, and hit Enter now.
那么 让我继续运行python of Students.py 然后现在按Enter键
And I think we'll see, indeed, Draco is now first.
我想我们会看到 的确 德拉科现在是第一个
Harry is second.
哈里是第二名
Hermione is third.
赫敏排名第三
And Ron is fourth.
罗恩是第四名
But this is arguably a little sloppy, right?
但这可以说是有点草率 对吗？
It seems a little hackish that I'm constructing these sentences.
我正在构造这些句子 这似乎有点老土
And even though I technically want to sort by name,
尽管从技术上讲我想按名字排序
I'm technically sorting by these whole English sentences.
从技术上讲 我是按这些完整的英语句子排序的
So it's not wrong.
所以这不是错的
It's achieving the intended result, but it's not really
它达到了预期的效果 但并不是真的
well designed because I'm just getting lucky that English
设计得很好 因为我很幸运 我的英语
is reading from left to right.
就是从左到右阅读
And therefore, when I print this out, it's sorting properly.
因此 当我打印出来时 它是正确排序的
It would be better, really, to come up with a technique for sorting
真的 想出一种分类的技术会更好
by the students' names, not by some English sentence
通过学生的名字 而不是通过一些英语句子
that I've constructed here on line 6.
我在第6行构建的
So to achieve this, I'm going to need to make my life more complicated
所以为了达到这个目的 我需要让我的生活变得更复杂
for a moment.
了一会儿.
And I'm going to need to collect information about each student
我需要收集每个学生的信息
before I bother assembling that sentence.
我才能把这句话说出来
So let me propose that we do this.
所以我建议我们这样做
Let me go ahead and undo these last few lines of code
让我继续撤消最后几行代码
so that we currently have two variables, name and house, each of which
所以我们现在有两个变量name和house 每个变量
has name and the student's house respectively.
分别有名字和学生的家
And we still have our global variable, students.
我们还有全局变量 学生
But let me do this.
但让我来吧
Recall that Python supports dictionaries.
回想一下Python支持字典
And dictionaries are just collections of keys and values.
字典只是键和值的集合
So you can associate something with something else,
所以你可以把一件事和另一件事联系起来
like, a name with Hermione, like, a house with Gryffindor.
比如赫敏的名字格兰芬多的房子
That really is a dictionary.
这真的是一本字典
So let me do this.
所以让我来吧
Let me temporarily create a dictionary that stores this association of name
让我临时创建一个字典来存储这个名称关联
with house.
关于House
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续做这个
Let me say that the student here is going to be represented initially
我要说的是 这里的学生将首先代表
by an empty dictionary.
一本空字典
And just like you can create an empty list with square brackets,
就像你可以用方括号创建一个空列表一样
you can create an empty dictionary with curly braces.
你可以用花括号创建一个空字典
So give me an empty dictionary that will soon have two keys, name and house.
所以给我一本空字典 它很快就会有两个关键词 名字和房子
How do I do that?
我该怎么做？
Well, I could do it this way-- student, open bracket,
我可以这样做学生式开放括号
name equals the student's name that we got from the line.
name等于我们从行中得到的学生的名字
Student, bracket, house equals the house that we got from the line.
学生 括号 房子等于我们从线上得到的房子
And now I'm going to append to the students list--
现在我将添加到学生列表中--
plural-- that particular student.
复数那个学生
Now, why have I done this?
我为什么要这么做？
I've admittedly made my code more complicated.
我承认我的代码变得更复杂了
It's more lines of code, but I've now collected
这是更多的代码行 但我现在已经收集了
all of the information I have about students while still keeping
所有我掌握的学生信息
track-- what's a name, what's a house.
什么是名字什么是房子
The list, meanwhile, has all of the students' names and houses together.
同时 名单上有所有学生的名字和房子
Now, why have I done this?
我为什么要这么做？
Well, let me, for the moment, just do something simple.
好吧 让我 暂时 做点简单的事
Let me do for student in students, and let me very simply now say, print
让我为学生们做一件事 现在让我非常简单地说 打印
the following f string, the current student with this name
下面的f字符串 当前同名的学生
is in this current student's house.
就在这个在校学生的房子里
And now notice one detail.
现在请注意一个细节
Inside of this f string, I'm using my curly braces, as always.
在这个f字符串中 我一如既往地使用我的花括号
I'm using, inside of those curly braces, the name of a variable, as always.
我一如既往地在花括号内使用变量的名称
But then I'm using not bracket 0 or 1 because these are dictionaries now,
但我用的不是方括号0或1 因为它们现在都是字典了
not list.
不是名单
But why am I using single quotes to surround house and to surround name?
但是为什么我要用单引号把House和名字括起来呢？
Why single quotes inside of this f string to access those keys?
为什么要在这个f字符串中使用单引号来访问这些键呢？
AUDIENCE: Yes, because you have double quotes in that line 12.
观众：是的 因为你在第12行有双引号
And so you have to tell Python to differentiate.
因此 您必须告诉Python要有所区别
DAVID MALAN: Exactly, because I'm already
大卫·马兰：没错 因为我已经
using double quotes outside of the f string, if I want to put quotes
在f字符串之外使用双引号 如果我想要加引号
around any strings on the inside, which I do
绕过内部的任何弦 我确实是这样做的
need to do for dictionaries because, recall, when you index
需要处理字典 因为 回想一下 当您索引时
into a dictionary, you don't use numbers like lists--
在词典中 你不会像列表一样使用数字--
0, 1, 2, onward--
0 1 2 向前--
you, instead, use strings, which need to be quoted.
相反 您使用的是字符串 需要用引号将其引起来
But if you're already using double quotes,
但如果你已经在用双引号了
it's easiest to then use single quotes on the inside,
最简单的做法是在内侧使用单引号
so Python doesn't get confused about what lines up with what.
因此 Python不会混淆什么与什么的关系
So at the moment, when I run this program,
所以现在 当我运行这个程序时
it's going to print out those hellos.
它将打印出这些问候
But they're not yet sorted.
但它们还没有被分类
In fact, what I now have is a list of dictionaries,
事实上 我现在拥有的是一份词典清单
and nothing is yet sorted.
而且目前还没有任何事情得到解决
But let me tighten up the code too to point out that it
但让我也收紧代码以指出它
doesn't need to be quite as verbose.
不需要那么冗长
If you're in the habit of creating an empty dictionary, like this on line 6,
如果您习惯于创建一本空词典 如第6行所示
and then immediately putting in two keys, name and house,
然后立即输入两把钥匙 名字和房子
each with two values, name and house respectively, you
每个值都有两个值 分别是name和house 您
can actually do this all at once.
实际上可以一次完成这一切
So let me show you a slightly different syntax.
因此 让我向您展示一个稍微不同的语法
I can do this.
我能做这些
Give me a variable called student, and let me use curly braces
给我一个名为Student的变量 让我使用花括号
on the right-hand side here.
在这里的右边
But instead of leaving them empty, let's just define those keys
但是 让我们只定义这些键 而不是将它们留空
and those values now.
以及现在的那些价值观
Quote/unquote name will be name, and quote/unquote house will be house.
引用/未引用的名称将是名称 引用/未引用的房子将是房子
This achieves the exact same effect in one line instead of three.
这在一行中实现了完全相同的效果 而不是三行
It creates a new non-empty dictionary containing a name key,
它创建一个包含名称键的新的非空词典
the value of which is the student's name,
它的值是学生的名字
and a house key, the value of which is the student's house.
和一把房子的钥匙 它的价值是学生的房子
Nothing else needs to change.
其他任何事情都不需要改变
That will still just work so that if I, again, run python of students.py,
这仍然是有效的 所以如果我再次运行python of Students.py
I'm still seeing those greetings, but they're still
我还能看到那些问候语 但它们仍然
not quite actually sorted.
实际上并没有完全分类
Well, what might I go about doing here in order to--
那么 我应该在这里做些什么才能--
what could I do to improve upon this further?
我能做些什么来进一步改进这一点呢？
Well, we need some mechanism now of sorting those students.
嗯 我们现在需要一些机制来对这些学生进行分类
But unfortunately, you can't do this.
但不幸的是 你不能这么做
We can't sort all of the students now because those students are not names
我们现在不能对所有学生进行排序 因为这些学生不是名字
like they were before.
就像以前一样
They aren't sentences
它们不再是以前的句子了
Each of the students is a dictionary, and it's not obvious
每个学生都是一本词典 这并不明显
how you would sort a dictionary inside of a list.
如何在列表中对词典进行排序
So ideally, what do we want to do?
所以在理想情况下 我们想要做什么？
If at the moment we hit line 9, we have a list of all of these students,
如果在我们到达第9行的那一刻 我们有所有这些学生的名单
and inside of that list is one dictionary per student,
在这份名单中 每个学生都有一本词典
and each of those dictionaries has two keys, name and house,
每本词典都有两个关键字 名字和房子
wouldn't it be nice if there were way in code to tell Python, sort this list
如果在代码中有方法告诉Python 对这个列表进行排序 那不是很好吗
by looking at this key in each dictionary?
通过在每本词典中查看这个关键字？
Because that would give us the ability to sort either by name, or even
因为这将使我们能够按名称甚至按名称进行排序
by house, or even by any other field that we add to that file.
按房屋 甚至按我们添加到该文件的任何其他字段
So it turns out, we can do this.
所以事实证明 我们可以做到这一点
We can tell the sorted function not just to reverse things or not.
我们可以告诉排序函数 不仅仅是反转还是不反转
It takes another positional--
它采取了另一种位置--
it takes another named parameter called key,
它接受另一个名为key的命名参数
where you can specify what key should be used in order to sort
其中 您可以指定应该使用哪个键来进行排序
some list of dictionaries.
一些词典的清单
And I'm going to propose that we do this.
我将提议我们这样做
I'm going to first define a function-- temporarily, for now-- called get_name.
我将首先定义一个名为get_name的函数--暂时是这样
And this function's purpose in life, given a student,
而这个功能在生活中的目的是 给一个学生
is to, quite simply, return the student's name
很简单 就是返回学生的名字
from that particular dictionary.
从那本特定的词典里
So if student is a dictionary, this is going to return literally
因此 如果学生是一本词典 它将按字面意思返回
the student's name, and that's it.
学生的名字 仅此而已
That's the sole purpose of this function in life.
这就是这个功能在生活中的唯一目的
What do I now want to do?
我现在想做什么？
Well now that I have a function that, given a student,
现在我有了一个函数 给定一个学生
will return to me the student's name, I can do this.
会把学生的名字还给我 我能做到
I can change sorted to say, use a key that's
我可以改成说 使用一把钥匙
equal to whatever the return value of get_name is.
等于GET_NAME的返回值
And this now is a feature of Python.
这现在是Python的一项功能
Python allows you to pass functions as arguments into other functions.
Python允许您将函数作为参数传递给其他函数
So get_name is a function.
所以GET_NAME是一个函数
Sorted is a function.
排序是一个函数
And I'm passing in get_name to sorted as the value of that key parameter.
我将GET_NAME作为该键参数的值传递给Sorted
Now, why am I doing that?
现在 我为什么要这么做？
Well, if you think of the get_name function,
好的 如果您想到get_name函数
it's just a block of code that will get the name of a student.
这只是一段代码 它将获得一个学生的名字
That's handy because that's the capability that sorted needs.
这很方便 因为这是对需求进行分类的功能
When given a list of students, each of which is a dictionary,
当给出一份学生名单时 每个学生都是一本词典
sorted needs to know, how do I get the name of the student?
分类需要知道的是 我怎么才能得到学生的名字？
In order to do alphabetical sorting for you.
以便按字母顺序为您排序
The authors of Python didn't know that we
Python的作者并不知道我们
were going to be creating students here in this class,
我们将在这个班级里创造学生
so they couldn't have anticipated writing code in advance
所以他们不可能预料到提前编写代码
that specifically sorts on a field called student, let alone called name,
它专门对一个名为Student的字段进行排序 更不用说名称了
let alone house.
更别提房子了
So what did they do?
那么他们做了什么呢？
They instead built into the sorted function
相反 它们内置于排序函数中
this named parameter key that allows us, all these years later,
这个命名的参数键允许我们 这么多年后
to tell their function sorted how to sort this list of dictionaries.
为了说明他们的功能 如何对这一系列词典进行排序
So now watch what happens.
所以 现在看看会发生什么
If I run python of students.py and hit Enter,
如果我运行PYTHON of Students.py并按Enter
I now have a sorted list of output.
我现在有了一个经过排序的输出列表
Why?
为什么？
Because now that list of dictionaries has all
因为现在这份词典列表里有
been sorted by the student's name.
已经按照学生的名字进行了分类
I can further do this.
我可以进一步做到这一点
If, as before, we want to reverse the whole thing by saying reverse
如果像以前一样 我们想要通过说Reverse来逆转整个事情
equals true, we can do that too.
这是真的 我们也可以这么做
Let me rerun Python of students.py, and hit Enter.
让我重新运行PYTHON of Students.py 然后按Enter键
Now it's reversed.
现在情况发生了逆转
Now it's Ron, then Hermione, Harry, and Draco.
现在是罗恩 然后是赫敏、哈利和德拉科
But we can do something different as well.
但我们也可以做一些不同的事情
What if I want to sort, for instance, by house name reversed?
例如 如果我想要按颠倒的房屋名称进行排序 该怎么办？
I could do this.
我能做到的
I could change this function from get_name to get_house.
我可以将此函数从get_name更改为get_house
I could change the implementation up here to be get_house.
我可以将这里的实现更改为Get_House
And I can return not the student's name but the student's house.
我可以退还的不是学生的名字 而是学生的房子
And so now notice, if I run python of students.py, Enter, notice now
现在请注意 如果我运行学生.py的python 请输入 现在请注意
it is sorted by house in reverse order.
它以相反的顺序按房屋排序
Slytherin is first, and then Gryffindor.
斯莱特林是第一名 然后是格兰芬多
If I get rid of the reverse but keep the get_house and rerun this program,
如果我取消反向操作 但保留Get_house并重新运行此程序
now it's sorted by house.
现在它是按房子分类的
Gryffindor is first, and Slytherin is last.
格兰芬多是第一个 斯莱特林是最后一个
And the upside now of this is, because I'm using this list of dictionaries
现在好的方面是 因为我用的是这一系列词典
and keeping the students data together until the last minute
并将学生数据保存在一起 直到最后一刻
when I'm finally doing the printing, I now
当我终于开始印刷的时候 我现在
have full control over the information itself, and I can sort by this or that.
对信息本身有完全的控制权 我可以按这个或那个排序
I don't have to construct those sentences in advance, like I
我不需要事先构思那些句子 就像我
rather hackishly did the first time.
第一次这样做是相当粗鲁的
All right, that was a lot.
好吧 那可真够多的
Let me pause here to see if there are questions.
让我在这里暂停一下 看看是否有问题
AUDIENCE: So when we are sorting the files, every time,
观众：所以当我们对文件进行分类时 每次
should we use the loops, or a text dictionary, or any kind of list?
我们应该使用循环、文本词典或任何类型的列表吗？
Can we sort by just sorting, not looping or any kind of stuff?
我们可以只按排序 而不是循环或任何类型的东西进行排序吗？
DAVID MALAN: A good question, and the short answer with Python
David Malan：这是一个很好的问题 也是对Python的简短回答
alone, you're the programmer.
独自一人 你是程序员
You need to do the sorting.
你需要进行分类
With libraries and other techniques, absolutely.
绝对可以使用库和其他技术
You can do more of this automatically because someone else
你可以自动完成更多的工作 因为其他人
has written that code.
已经编写了这段代码
What we're doing at the moment is doing everything from scratch ourselves.
我们目前所做的一切都是自己从头开始做
But absolutely, with other functions or libraries, some of this
但绝对可以使用其他函数或库 其中一些
could be made more easily done.
可以变得更容易做到
Some of this could be made easier.
这其中的一些事情可以变得更容易
Other questions on this technique here?
这里还有关于这项技术的其他问题吗？
AUDIENCE: If equal to the return value of the function,
受众：如果等于函数的返回值
can it be equal to just a variable or a value?
它能否仅等于一个变量或一个值？
DAVID MALAN: Well, yes.
大卫·马兰：嗯 是的
It should equal a value.
它应该等于一个值
And I should clarify, actually, since this was not obvious.
事实上 我应该澄清一下 因为这并不明显
So when you pass in a function like get_name or get_house
因此 当您传入一个像get_name或get_house这样的函数时
to the sorted function as the value of key,
将排序后的函数作为key的值
that function is automatically called by the sorted function for you
排序后的函数会自动调用该函数
on each of the dictionaries in the list.
在列表中的每一本词典上
And it uses the return value of get_name or get_house
并使用GET_NAME或GET_HOUSE的返回值
to decide what strings to actually use to compare in order to decide
决定实际使用哪些字符串进行比较 以便决定
which is alphabetically correct.
按字母顺序排列是正确的
So this function, which you pass just by name, you
因此 这个仅按名称传递的函数 您
do not pass in parentheses at the end, is
不要在末尾加上圆括号 是
called by the sorted function in order to figure out for you
由排序函数调用 以便为您计算
how to compare these same values.
如何比较这些相同的值
AUDIENCE: How can we use nested dictionaries?
听众：我们怎样才能使用嵌套词典？
I have read about nested dictionaries.
我读过关于嵌套词典的文章
What is the difference between nested dictionaries
嵌套词典之间有什么不同
and the dictionary inside a list?
清单里的字典呢？
I think it is that.
我想就是这个原因
DAVID MALAN: Sure.
大卫·马兰：当然
So we are using a list of dictionaries.
因此 我们使用了一系列词典
Why?
为什么？
Because each of those dictionaries represents a student.
因为每一本词典都代表一个学生
And a student has a name and a house, and we want to, I claim,
一个学生有一个名字和一所房子 我们想 我说
maintain that association.
保持这种联系
And it's a list of students because we've got multiple students-- four,
这是一个学生名单 因为我们有多个学生--四个
in this case.
在这种情况下
You could create a structure that is a dictionary of dictionaries.
您可以创建一个结构 它是词典的词典
But I would argue, it just doesn't solve a problem.
但我会争辩说 这根本解决不了问题
I don't need a dictionary of dictionary.
我不需要一本词典
I need a list of key-value pairs right now.
我现在需要一份键-值对的列表
That's all.
就这样
So let me propose, if we go back to students.py here,
所以让我提议 如果我们回到Students.py这里
and we revert back to the approach where we have get_name as the function,
我们又回到了将get_name作为函数的方法中
both used and defined here, and that function returns the student's name,
都在这里使用和定义 并且该函数返回学生的名字
what happens to be clear is that the sorted function will use the value
可以肯定的是 排序后的函数将使用
of key-- get_name, in this case--
密钥的--在本例中为get_name--
calling that function on every dictionary in the list
在列表中的每个词典上调用该函数
that it's supposed to sort.
它应该是分类的
And that function, get_name, returns the string
该函数GET_NAME返回字符串
that sorted will actually use to decide whether things
它实际上将被用来决定事物是否
go in this order, left-right, or in this order, right-left.
按这个顺序走 从左到右 或者按这个顺序 从右到左
It alphabetizes these things based on that return value.
它根据返回值对这些内容进行字母排序
So notice that I'm not calling the function get_name here
因此请注意 我在这里并没有调用函数get_name
with parentheses.
加上圆括号
I'm passing it in only by its name so that the sorted function
我只按其名称传递它 以便排序后的函数
can call that get name function for me.
可以为我调用那个获取名称函数
Now, it turns out, as always, if you're defining something,
现在 事实证明 一如既往地 如果你在定义某事
be it a variable or, in this case, a function, and then immediately using
可以是一个变量 或者在本例中是一个函数 然后立即使用
it but never, once again, needing the name of that function,
但它再也不需要该函数的名称了
like, get_name, we can actually tighten this code up further.
例如 get_name 我们实际上可以进一步加强这段代码
I can actually do this.
我真的能做到
I can get rid of the get_name function all together,
我可以一起去掉get_name函数
just like I could get rid of a variable that isn't strictly necessary.
就像我可以去掉一个严格来说不是必需的变量一样
And instead of passing key, the name of a function,
而不是传递密钥 即函数的名称
I can actually pass key what's called a lambda
我实际上可以传递密钥 也就是所谓的lambda
function, which is an anonymous function, a function that
函数 这是一个匿名函数 该函数
just has no name.
只是没有名字
Why?
为什么？
Because you don't need to give it a name if you're only going to call it in one
因为你不需要给它一个名字 如果你只在一个地方叫它的话
place.
地点
And the syntax for this in Python is a little weird.
而在Python中实现这一点的语法有点奇怪
But if I do key equals literally the word lambda, then something
但如果Key从字面上等于lambda 那么有些东西
like student, which is the name of the parameter
如Student 它是参数的名称
I expect this function to take, and then I don't even type the Return key.
我希望这个函数会起作用 然后我甚至不会键入回车键
I instead just say, student, bracket, name.
相反 我只是说 学生 括号 名字
So what am I doing here with my code?
那么我带着我的代码在这里做什么呢？
This code here that I've highlighted is equivalent to the get_name function
我突出显示的这段代码相当于get_name函数
I implemented a moment ago.
我刚才实施了
The syntax is admittedly a little different.
无可否认 语法略有不同
I don't use def.
我不用def
I didn't even give it a name, like get_name.
I didn't even give it a name, like get_name.
I, instead, am using this other keyword in Python called lambda, which says,
I, instead, am using this other keyword in Python called lambda, which says,
hey, Python, here comes a function, but it has no name.
hey, Python, here comes a function, but it has no name.
It's anonymous.
It's anonymous.
That function takes a parameter.
That function takes a parameter.
I could call it anything I want.
I could call it anything I want.
I'm calling it student.
I'm calling it student.
Why?
Why?
Because this function that's passed in as key
Because this function that's passed in as key
is called on every one of the students in that list,
is called on every one of the students in that list,
every one of the dictionaries in that list.
every one of the dictionaries in that list.
What do I want this anonymous function to return?
What do I want this anonymous function to return?
Well given a student, I want to index into that dictionary
Well given a student, I want to index into that dictionary
and access their name so that the string Hermione, and Harry, and Ron,
and access their name so that the string Hermione, and Harry, and Ron,
and Draco is ultimately returned.
and Draco is ultimately returned.
And that's what the sorted function uses to decide
And that's what the sorted function uses to decide
how to sort these bigger dictionaries that have other keys, like house,
how to sort these bigger dictionaries that have other keys, like house,
as well.
as well.
So if I now go back to my terminal window and run python of students.py,
So if I now go back to my terminal window and run python of students.py,
it still seems to work the same, but it's arguably a little better design
it still seems to work the same, but it's arguably a little better design
because I didn't waste lines of code by defining some other function,
because I didn't waste lines of code by defining some other function,
calling it in one and only one place.
calling it in one and only one place.
I've done it all sort of in one breath, if you will.
I've done it all sort of in one breath, if you will.
All right, let me pause here to see if there's any questions specifically
All right, let me pause here to see if there's any questions specifically
about lambda, or anonymous functions, and this tightening up of the code.
about lambda, or anonymous functions, and this tightening up of the code.
AUDIENCE: I have a question, like whether we could define lambda twice.
AUDIENCE: I have a question, like whether we could define lambda twice.
DAVID MALAN: You can use lambda twice.
DAVID MALAN: You can use lambda twice.
You can create as many anonymous functions as you'd like.
You can create as many anonymous functions as you'd like.
And you generally use them in contexts like this,
And you generally use them in contexts like this,
where you want to pass to some other function
where you want to pass to some other function
a function that itself does not need a name.
a function that itself does not need a name.
So you can absolutely use it in more than one place.
So you can absolutely use it in more than one place.
I just have only one use case for it.
I just have only one use case for it.
How about one other question on lambda or anonymous functions specifically?
How about one other question on lambda or anonymous functions specifically?
AUDIENCE: What if our lambda would take more than one line, for example?
AUDIENCE: What if our lambda would take more than one line, for example?
DAVID MALAN: Sure, if your lambda function takes
DAVID MALAN: Sure, if your lambda function takes
multiple parameters, that is fine.
多个参数 这很好
You can simply specify commas followed by the names of those parameters,
您可以简单地指定逗号 后跟这些参数的名称
maybe x and y or so forth, after the name student.
也许是x和y等等 在学生这个名字之后
So here too, lambda looks a little different
所以在这里 lambda看起来也有点不同
from def in that you don't have parentheses,
从def开始 因为你没有括号
you don't have the keyword def, you don't have a function name.
您没有关键字def 也没有函数名
But ultimately, they achieve that same effect.
但最终 它们会达到同样的效果
They create a function anonymously and allow you to pass it in,
它们以匿名方式创建一个函数 并允许您传递该函数
for instance, as some value here.
例如 作为这里的一些价值
So let's now change students.csv to contain
现在 让我们将Students.csv更改为包含
not students' houses at Hogwarts, but their homes where they grew up.
不是霍格沃茨的学生家 而是他们长大的家
So Draco, for instance, grew up in Malfoy Manor.
以德拉科为例 他在马尔福庄园长大
Ron grew up in The Burrow.
罗恩在洞穴里长大
Harry grew up in Number Four, Privet Drive.
哈里在女贞路4号长大
And according to the internet, no one knows where Hermione grew up.
根据互联网上的说法 没有人知道赫敏在哪里长大
The movies apparently took certain liberties with where she grew up.
显然 这些电影对她成长的地方采取了一定的自由
So for this purpose, we're actually going
因此 为了这个目的 我们实际上要
to remove Hermione because it is unknown exactly where she was born.
将赫敏带走 因为她的确切出生地尚不清楚
So we still have some three students.
所以我们还有三个学生
But if anyone can spot the potential problem now,
但如果有人现在就能发现潜在的问题
how might this be a bad thing?
这怎么可能是一件坏事呢？
Well, let's go and try and run our own code here.
好了 让我们来尝试在这里运行我们自己的代码
Let me go back to students.py here.
让我回到Students.Py这里
And let me propose that I just change my semantics
让我提议我只是改变我的语义
because I'm now not thinking about Hogwarts houses but the students'
因为我现在想的不是霍格沃茨的房子 而是学生们的
own homes.
拥有自己的家
So I'm just going to change some variables.
所以我只需要改变一些变量
I'm going to change this house to a home, this house to a home,
我要把这个房子变成一个家 把这个房子变成一个家
as well as this one here.
就像这里的这个一样
I'm still going to sort the students by name,
我仍然会按学生的名字进行排序
but I'm going to say that they're not in a house, but rather, from a home.
但我要说的是 他们不是在一所房子里 而是来自一个家庭
So I've just changed the names of my variables and my grammar in English
所以我刚刚用英语更改了变量的名称和语法
here, ultimately, to print out that, for instance, Harry
在这里 最终 打印出来 例如 哈里
is from Number Four, Privet Drive, and so forth.
是从女贞路4号来的 等等
But let's see what happens here when I run
但让我们看看当我跑的时候会发生什么
Python of this version of students.py, having changed students.csv
此版本的Students.py的Python 已经更改了Students.csv
to contain those homes and not houses.
来控制那些房屋而不是房屋
Enter.
进来吧
Huh, our first value error, like the program just doesn't work.
嗯 我们的第一个值错误 就像程序就是不工作
What might explain this value error?
如何解释这个值错误？
The explanation of which rather cryptically
对此的解释相当隐晦
is, too many values to unpack.
是 太多的价值无法拆开
And the line in question is this one involving split.
而有问题的是这条涉及Split的线
How did, all of a sudden, after all of these successful runs of this program,
怎么突然之间 在这个项目成功运行了这么多年之后
did line 5 suddenly now break?
5号线现在突然断了吗？
AUDIENCE: In the line in students.csv, you have three values.
观众：在Students.csv中的这一行中 您有三个值
There's a line that you have three values and in students.
有一句话说 你有三种价值观 在学生身上
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, I spent a lot of time trying
大卫·马兰：是的 我花了很多时间尝试
to figure out where every student should be from so that we
找出每个学生应该来自哪里 这样我们就可以
could create this problem for us.
可能会给我们带来这个问题
And wonderfully, like, the first sentence of the book
奇妙的是 就像这本书的第一句话
is Number Four, Privet Drive.
是女贞路四号
And so the fact that address has a comma in it is problematic.
因此 地址中有逗号这一事实是有问题的
Why?
为什么？
Because you and I decided sometime ago to just standardize on commas--
因为你和我在一段时间前决定将逗号标准化--
CSV, Comma-Separated Values-- to denote the--
CSV 逗号分隔值--表示--
we standardized on commas in order to delineate one value from another.
我们对逗号进行了标准化 以便将一个值与另一个值分开
And if we have commas grammatically in the student's home,
如果我们在学生家里用逗号
we're clearly confusing it as this special symbol.
我们显然把它混淆为这个特殊的符号
And the split function is now, for just Harry,
分裂函数现在是 仅对哈里而言
trying to split it into three values, not just two.
试图把它分成三个值 而不仅仅是两个值
And that's why there's too many values to unpack
这就是为什么有太多的价值需要拆解
because we're only trying to assign two variables, name and house.
因为我们只想给两个变量赋值 名字和房子
Now, what could we do here?
现在 我们在这里能做些什么呢？
Well, we could just change our approach, for instance.
嗯 例如 我们可以改变我们的方法
One paradigm that is not uncommon is to use something a little less common,
一种并不罕见的范例是使用一些不太常见的东西
like a vertical bar.
就像一根竖条
So I could go in and change all of my commas to vertical bars.
这样我就可以把我所有的逗号改成竖线了
That, too, could eventually come back to bite us
它最终也可能回来咬我们
in that if my file eventually has vertical bars somewhere,
因为如果我的文件最终在某处有竖线
it might still break.
它仍然有可能坏掉
So maybe that's not the best approach.
因此 这可能不是最好的方法
I could maybe do something like this.
我也许可以做这样的事
I could escape the data, as I've done in the past.
我可以逃避这些数据 就像我过去所做的那样
And maybe I could put quotes around any English string
也许我可以在任何英文字符串两边加引号
that itself contains a comma.
它本身包含一个逗号
And that's fine.
这很好
I could do that, but then my code, students.py,
我可以这么做 但是我的代码 Students.py
is going to have to change too because I can't just naively split on
也必须改变 因为我不能天真地分裂
a comma now.
现在是逗号
I'm going to have to be smarter about it.
在这件事上我得变得更聪明一些
take into account split
我将不得不考虑到斯普利特
only on the commas that are not inside of quotes.
仅限于不在引号内的逗号
And oh, it's getting complicated fast.
哦 事情变得越来越复杂了
And at this point, you need to take a step back and consider,
在这一点上 你需要退一步考虑
you know what, if we're having this problem, odds are, many other people
你知道吗 如果我们有这样的问题 很有可能 其他很多人
before us have had this same problem.
在我们之前也有过同样的问题
It is incredibly common to store data in files.
将数据存储在文件中是非常常见的
It is incredibly common to use CSV files specifically.
专门使用CSV文件是非常常见的
And so you know what.
所以你知道吗
Why don't we see if there's a library in Python that
为什么我们不看看在Python语言中是否有一个库
exists to read and/or write CSV files?
是否存在读取和/或写入CSV文件的功能？
Rather than reinvent the wheel, so to speak,
与其重新发明轮子 可以说
let's see if we can write better code by standing on the shoulders of others who
让我们看看我们是否可以通过站在其他人的肩膀上来编写更好的代码
have come before us-- programmers passed--
在我们之前--程序员们过去了--
and actually use their code to do the reading and writing of CSVs,
并实际使用他们的代码来读取和写入CSV
so we can focus on the part of our problem that you and I care about.
这样我们就可以专注于你我关心的那部分问题了
So let's propose that we go back to our code here
因此 让我们建议我们回到这里的代码
and see how we might use the CSV library.
看看我们可以如何使用CSV库
Indeed, within Python, there is a module called CSV.
事实上 在Python中 有一个名为CSV的模块
The documentation for it is at this URL here
有关它的文档位于此处的URL
in Python's official documentation.
在Python的官方文档中
But there's a few functions that are pretty readily accessible if we just
但有几个功能是很容易访问的 如果我们只是
dive right in.
一头扎进去
And let me propose that we do this.
让我提议我们这样做
Let me go back to my code here.
让我在这里回到我的代码
And instead of re-inventing this wheel and reading the file line by line,
而不是重新发明这个轮子 逐行阅读文件
and splitting on commas, and dealing now with quotes, and Privet Drives,
和逗号拆分 现在处理引号和女贞驱动器
and so forth, let's do this instead.
以此类推 让我们改为这样做
At the start of my program, let me go up and import the CSV module.
在我的程序开始时 让我启动并导入CSV模块
Let's use this library that someone else has
让我们使用别人拥有的这个库
written that's dealing with all of these corner cases, if you will.
如果你愿意的话 写的是处理所有这些角落案件的书
I'm still going to give myself a list, initially empty,
我还是会给自己列一张清单 一开始是空的
in which to store all these students.
用来存放所有这些学生的地方
But I'm going to change my approach here now just a little bit.
但我现在要稍微改变一下我的方法
When I open this file with with, let me go in here
当我用打开这个文件时 让我进入这里
and change this a little bit.
对此稍加改动
I'm going to go in here now and say this.
我现在要进去说这句话
Reader equals csv.reader, passing in file as input.
Reader等于csv.ader 将文件作为输入传入
So it turns out, if you read the documentation for the CSV module,
事实证明 如果您阅读CSV模块的文档
it comes with a function called reader whose purpose in life
它附带一个名为Reader的功能 该功能的目的是
is to read a CSV file for you and figure out, where are the commas, where
是为您读取CSV文件并找出逗号在哪里、在哪里
are the quotes, where are all the potential corner cases,
是引语 所有可能的转折点都在哪里
and just deal with them for you.
只为你处理这些问题
You can override certain defaults or assumptions in case
您可以覆盖某些默认设置或假设 以防
you're using not a comma, but a pipe or something else.
您使用的不是逗号 而是竖线或其他什么
But by default, I think it's just going to work.
但在默认情况下 我认为它只是会奏效
Now, how do I integrate over a reader and not the raw file itself?
现在 我如何通过读取器而不是原始文件本身进行集成？
It's almost the same.
这几乎是一样的
The library allows you still to do this.
该库仍允许您执行此操作
For each row in the reader--
对于阅读器中的每一行-
so you're not iterating over the file directly now.
所以您现在不是直接迭代文件
You're iterating over the reader, which is, again,
你是在重复读者 也就是
going to handle all of the parsing of commas, and new lines, and more.
将处理所有逗号和换行符的解析 等等
For each row in the reader, what am I going to do?
对于阅读器中的每一行 我要做什么？
Well, at the moment, I'm going to do this.
好吧 现在 我要这么做了
I'm going to append to my students list the following dictionary, a dictionary
我要在我的学生名单上附上下面的词典 一本词典
that has a name whose value is the current row's first column,
其名称的值是当前行的第一列
and whose house, or rather, home now is the row's second.
谁的房子 或者更确切地说 现在是这排的第二个家
column.
纵队
Now, it's worth noting that the reader for each line in the file,
现在 值得注意的是 文件中每一行的阅读器
indeed, returns to me a row.
的确 还给我排了一排
But it returns to me a row that's a list, which
但它向我返回一行 这是一个列表
is to say that the first element of that list
就是说这个列表的第一个元素
is going to be the student's name, as before.
将是学生的名字 就像以前一样
The second element of that list is going to be the student's home, as now
列表中的第二个元素将是学生的家 就像现在一样
before.
在此之前
But if I want to access each of those elements,
但如果我想访问这些元素中的每一个
remember that lists are 0 indexed.
请记住 列表是0索引的
We start counting at 0 and then 1, rather than 1 and then 2.
我们从0开始计数 然后是1 而不是1 然后是2
So if I want to get at the student's name, I use row, bracket, 0.
所以如果我想知道学生的名字 我会用行 括号 0
And if I want to get at the student's home, I use row, bracket, 1.
如果我想去学生家 我会用ROW WARKET 1
But in my for loop, we can do that same unpacking as before.
但在我的for循环中 我们可以像以前一样进行解包
If I know the CSV is only going to have two columns,
如果我知道CSV只有两列
I could even do this-- for name, home in reader.
我甚至可以这样做--以名字命名 在Reader中回家
And now I don't need to use list notation.
现在我不需要使用列表表示法了
I can unpack things all at once and say, name here, and home here.
我可以一下子打开所有的东西 然后说 名字在这里 家在这里
The rest of my code can stay exactly the same because,
我的其余代码可以完全保持不变 因为
what am I doing now on line 8?
我现在在8号线上做什么？
I'm still constructing the same dictionary as before,
我仍然在构建和以前一样的词典
albeit for homes instead of houses.
尽管是为了房子而不是房子
And I'm grabbing those values now, not from the file itself
我现在正在获取这些值 而不是从文件本身
and my use of split, but the reader.
以及我对Split的使用 但读者
And again, what the reader is going to do
再说一次 读者要做的是
is figure out, where are those commas, where are the quotes?
找出那些逗号在哪里 引号在哪里？
And just solve that problem for you.
为你解决这个问题
So let me go now down to my terminal window and run python of students.py,
现在让我转到我的终端窗口 运行python of Students.py
and hit Enter.
然后按Enter键
And now we see successfully, sorted no less, that Draco is from Malfoy Manor.
现在 我们成功地看到 德拉科来自马尔福庄园
Harry is from Number Four, comma, Privet Drive.
哈里来自女贞路4号 逗号
And Ron is from The Burrow.
而罗恩是从地穴来的
Questions now on this technique of using CSV reader from that CSV module, which,
现在关于从CSV模块使用CSV读取器技术的问题
again, is just getting us out of the business of reading each line ourself
又一次 让我们摆脱了自己阅读每一行文字的麻烦
and reading each of those commas and splitting?
然后阅读每一个逗号并拆分？
AUDIENCE: So my questions are related to something in the past.
观众：所以我的问题跟过去的事情有关
I recognize that you are reading a file every time--
我知道你每次都在看文件--
well, we assume that we have the CSV file to hand already in this case.
在本例中 我们假设已经有了CSV文件
Is it possible to make a file readable and writable?
是否有可能使文件可读可写？
So in this case, you could write such stuff to the file,
因此 在这种情况下 您可以将这些内容写入文件
but then at the same time, you could have
但同时 你也可以
another function that reads through the file and does changes to it
另一个读取文件并对其进行更改的函数
as you go along?
当你继续前进的时候？
DAVID MALAN: A really good question.
大卫·马兰：这是一个非常好的问题
And the short answer is, yes.
简短的回答是 是的
However, historically, the mental model for a file is that of a cassette tape.
然而 从历史上看 文件的心理模型是盒式磁带
Years ago, not really in use anymore, but cassette tapes
几年前 已经不再使用了 但盒式磁带
are sequential whereby they start at the beginning,
是连续的 因此它们从开始处开始
and if you want to get to the end, you kind of
如果你想读到最后 你就有点
have to unwind the tape to get to that point.
必须把带子倒出来才能做到这一点
The closest analog nowadays would be something like Netflix or any streaming
如今最接近的类比将是Netflix或任何流媒体
service, where there's a scrubber that you have to go left to right.
服务 那里有一个洗涤器 你必须从左到右
You can't just jump there or jump there.
你不能跳到那里或者跳到那里
You don't have random access.
你没有随机访问权限
So the problem with files, if you want to read and write them,
所以文件的问题是 如果你想读写它们
you or some library needs to keep track of where you are in the file
您或某个库需要跟踪您在文件中的位置
so that if you're reading from the top and then you write at the bottom,
因此 如果你从顶部阅读 然后在底部写作
and you want to start reading again, you seek back to the beginning.
当你想重新开始阅读时 你需要回到开始的地方
So it's not something we'll do here in class.
所以这不是我们在课堂上要做的事情
It's more involved, but it's absolutely doable.
它的涉及面更广 但绝对可行
For our purposes, we'll generally recommend, read the file.
出于我们的目的 我们通常建议您阅读该文件
And then if you want to change it, write it back out,
然后 如果你想改变它 把它写回来
rather than trying to make more piecemeal changes, which is good
而不是试图做出更多零碎的改变 这是好的
if, though, the file is massive, and it would just be very expensive
但是 如果文件很大 而且会非常昂贵
time-wise to change the whole thing.
改变这整件事是明智的
Other questions on this CSV reader?
关于这个CSV阅读器还有其他问题吗？
AUDIENCE: It's possible to write a paragraph in that file?
听众：可以在那个文件里写一段话吗？
DAVID MALAN: Absolutely.
大卫·马兰：当然
Right now, I'm writing very small strings, just names or houses,
现在 我正在写很小的字符串 只写名字或房子
as I did before.
就像我以前做的那样
But you can absolutely write as much text as you want, indeed.
但事实上 你完全可以想写多少文本就写多少文本
Other questions on CSV reader?
关于CSV阅读器的其他问题？
AUDIENCE: Can a user chose himself a key?
观众：用户可以自己选择一把钥匙吗？
Like, input key will be a name or code.
例如 输入键将是一个名称或代码
DAVID MALAN: So short answer, yes, we could absolutely
大卫·马兰：答案很简单 是的 我们完全可以
write a program that prompts the user for a name
编写一个提示用户输入名称的程序
and a home, a name and a home.
还有一个家 一个名字和一个家
And we could write out those values.
我们可以写出这些值
And in a moment, we'll see how you can write to a CSV file.
稍后 我们将了解如何写入CSV文件
For now, I'm assuming, as the programmer who created students.csv, that I
现在 我假设 作为创建Students.csv的程序员 我
know what the columns are going to be.
知道栏目会是什么
And therefore, I'm naming my variables accordingly.
因此 我相应地给我的变量命名
However, this is a good segue to one final feature of reading CSVs, which
然而 这是阅读CSV的最后一个特性的一个很好的片段 它
is that you don't have to rely on either getting a row as a list
就是您不必依赖于以列表形式获得行
and using bracket 0 or bracket 1, and, you don't have
并且使用方括号0或方括号1 并且 您没有
to unpack things manually in this way.
以这种方式手动拆包
We could actually be smarter and start storing
我们实际上可以变得更聪明 开始储存
the names of these columns in the CSV file itself.
CSV文件本身中这些列的名称
And in fact, if any of you have ever opened a spreadsheet file before, be it
事实上 如果你们中的任何人以前打开过电子表格文件
in Excel, Apple Numbers, Google Spreadsheets or the like, odds are,
在Excel、Apple数字、谷歌电子表格或类似的东西中 可能性是
you've noticed that the first row, very frequently, is a little different.
您已经注意到 第一行经常会有一些不同
It actually is boldface sometimes, or it actually
它实际上有时是黑体 或者实际上
contains the names of those columns, the names of those attributes below.
包含这些列的名称 下面是这些属性的名称
And we can do this here.
我们可以在这里做到这一点
In students.csv, I don't have to just keep
在Students.csv中 我不必只保持
assuming that the student's name is first
假设学生的名字放在第一位
and that the student's home is second.
学生的家排在第二位
I can explicitly bake that information into the file just
我可以显式地将该信息烘焙到文件中
to reduce the probability of mistakes down the road.
以减少未来出错的可能性
I can literally use the first row of this file and say, name, comma, home.
从字面上看 我可以使用这个文件的第一行 然后说 名字 逗号 家
So notice that name is not literally someone's name,
所以请注意 名字并不是字面上的某人的名字
and home is not literally someone's home.
家并不是一个人的家
It is literally the words, name and home, separated by comma.
它的字面意思是单词、名字和家 用逗号分隔
And if I now go back into students.py and don't use CSV reader,
如果我现在返回到Students.py 并且不使用CSV阅读器
but instead, I use a dictionary reader, I
但我用的是词典阅读器 我
can actually treat my CSV file even more flexibly, not just for this,
我实际上可以更灵活地处理我的CSV文件 不仅仅是为了这个
but for other examples too.
但对于其他例子也是如此
Let me do this.
让我来做吧
Instead of using a CSV reader, let me use
与其使用CSV阅读器 不如让我使用
a CSV dict reader, which will now iterate over the file top to bottom,
CSV字典阅读器 现在将从上到下迭代文件
loading in each line of text not as a list of columns
加载到每行文本中 而不是作为列的列表
but as a dictionary of columns.
而是作为一本栏目词典
What's nice about this is that it's going
这件事的好处是它正在进行
to give me automatic access now to those columns' names.
让我现在可以自动访问这些栏目的名称
I'm going to revert to just saying, for row in reader,
我将回到刚才说的 在读者中排
and now I'm going to append a name and a home.
现在我要附加一个名字和一个家
But how am I going to get access to the current row's
但是我如何才能访问当前行的
name and the current row's home?
名字和当前这一排的家？
Well, earlier, I used bracket 0 for the first and bracket 1 for the second
好的 前面我用括号0表示第一个 用括号1表示第二个
when I was using a reader.
当我在使用阅读器的时候
A reader returns lists.
阅读器返回列表
A dict reader or dictionary reader returns dictionaries, one at a time.
词典阅读器或词典阅读器一次返回一个词典
And so if I want to access the current row's name,
因此 如果我想访问当前行的名称
I can say, row, quote/unquote, name.
我可以说 行 引号/不引号 名字
I can say here for home, row, quote/unquote, home.
我可以在这里说家 行 引用/不引用 家
And I now have access to those same values.
我现在可以接触到这些相同的价值观
The only change I had to make, to be clear, was in my CSV file,
明确地说 我需要做的唯一更改是在我的CSV文件中
I had to include, on the very first row, little hints
我不得不在第一行加上一些小提示
as to what these columns are.
这些栏目是什么
And if I now run this code, I think it should behave pretty much
如果我现在运行这段代码 我认为它应该表现得相当好
the same-- python of students.py.
相同的--Students.py的蟒蛇
And indeed, we get the same sentences.
事实上 我们得到的是同样的句子
But now my code is more robust against changes in this data.
但现在 我的代码对此数据的更改更加健壮
If I were to open the CSV file in Excel, or Google Spreadsheets, or Apple
如果我在Excel、Google电子表格或Apple中打开CSV文件
Numbers, and for whatever reason change the columns around,
数字 无论出于什么原因 都会改变周围的列
maybe this is a file that you're sharing with someone else,
也许这是您与其他人共享的文件
and just because, they decide to sort things differently left
仅仅因为 他们决定以不同的方式对事物进行分类
to right by moving the columns around, previously, my code
向右移动列 以前 我的代码
would have broken because I was assuming that name is always first,
因为我以为名字总是排在第一位
and home is always second.
家永远是第二位的
But if I did this--
但如果我这么做了
be it manually in one of those programs or here-- home, comma, name,
无论是在其中一个程序中手动设置 还是在这里--Home、逗号、姓名、
and suppose, I reversed all of this.
假设 我扭转了这一切
The home comes first, followed by Harry, The Burrow, then by Ron,
家是第一位的 紧随其后的是哈里 地穴 然后是罗恩
and then lastly, Malfoy Manor, then Draco,
最后是马尔福庄园 然后是德拉科
notice that my file is now completely flipped.
请注意 我的文件现在完全翻转了
The first column is now the second, and the second's the first.
第一列现在是第二列 第二列是第一列
But I took care to update the header of that file, the first row.
但我小心地更新了该文件的头 即第一行
Notice my Python code, I'm not going to touch it at all.
请注意我的Python代码 我根本不会去碰它
I'm going to rerun python of students.py, and hit Enter.
我将重新运行python of Students.py 然后按Enter键
And it still just works.
而且它仍然很管用
And this, too, is an example of coding defensively.
这也是防御性编码的一个例子
What if someone changes your CSV file, your data file?
如果有人更改了您的CSV文件、数据文件 该怎么办？
Ideally, that won't happen.
理想情况下 这种情况不会发生
But even if it does now, because I'm using a dictionary reader that's
但即使现在是这样 因为我使用的是一个词典阅读器
going to infer from that first row for me what the columns are called,
我将从第一行中推断出这些列的名称
my code just keeps working.
我的代码一直在工作
And so it keeps getting, if you will, better and better.
因此 如果你愿意的话 它会变得越来越好
Any questions now on this approach?
现在对这种方法有什么问题吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah, what is the importance of new line in the CSV file?
观众：是的 CSV文件中新行的重要性是什么？
DAVID MALAN: What's the importance of the new line in the CSV file?
David Malan：CSV文件中新行的重要性是什么？
It's partly a convention.
这在一定程度上是一种惯例
In the world of text files, we humans have just
在文本文件的世界里 我们人类只有
been, for decades, in the habit of storing data line by line.
几十年来 我一直保持着逐行存储数据的习惯
It's visually convenient.
它在视觉上很方便
It's just easy to extract from the file because you just
它很容易从文件中提取 因为您只需
look for the new lines.
寻找新的台词
So the new line just separates some data from some other data.
因此 新的行只是将一些数据与其他一些数据分开
We could use any other symbol on the keyboard,
我们可以在键盘上使用任何其他符号
but it's just common to hit Enter to just move the data to the next line.
但按Enter键只是为了将数据移到下一行 这是很常见的
Just a convention.
这只是个会议
Other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
AUDIENCE: It seems to be working fine if you just have name and home.
观众：如果你只有名字和家庭 它似乎运行得很好
I'm wondering what will happen if you want to put in more data.
我在想 如果你想输入更多的数据 会发生什么
Say, you wanted to add a house to both the name and the home.
比方说 你想在名字和房子的基础上加一栋房子
DAVID MALAN: Sure, if you wanted to add the house back-- so if I go in here
大卫·马兰：当然可以 如果你想把房子加回去--所以如果我进去
and add house last, and I go here and say, Gryffindor for Harry,
最后加上豪斯 我在这里说 格兰芬多代表哈利
Gryffindor for Ron, and Slytherin for Draco, now I have three columns,
格兰芬多代表罗恩 斯莱特林代表德拉科 现在我有三个专栏
effectively, if you will-- home on the left, name in the middle,
实际上 如果你愿意的话--家在左边 名字在中间
house on the right, each separated by commas with weird things,
右边的房子 每个房子都用逗号分隔 上面有奇怪的东西
like Number Four, comma, Privet Drive still quoted.
像第四个一样 逗号 女贞路仍然被引用
Notice, if I go back to students.py, and I don't change the code at all
请注意 如果我返回到Students.py 并且我根本不更改代码
and run python of students.py, it still just works.
并运行python of Students.py 它仍然可以正常工作
And this is what's so powerful about a dictionary reader.
这就是字典阅读器的强大之处
It can change over time.
它可以随着时间的推移而改变
It can have more and more columns.
它可以有越来越多的列
Your existing code is not going to break.
您现有的代码不会崩溃
Your code would break, would be much more fragile, so to speak,
可以说 你的密码会被破解 会变得更加脆弱
if you were making assumptions like, the first column's always going to be name.
如果你做这样的假设 第一栏总是名字
The second column is always going to be house.
第二列永远是豪斯
Things will break fast if those assumptions break down--
如果这些假设被打破 事情将很快破裂--
so not a problem in this case.
所以在这种情况下不是问题
Well, let me propose that, besides reading CSVs,
好吧 让我提议 除了阅读CSV
let's at least take a peek at how we might write a CSV too.
至少让我们来看看我们可能会如何编写一个CSV
If you're writing a program in which you want to store not just students' names,
如果您正在编写一个程序 其中不仅要存储学生的名字
but maybe their homes as well in a file, how can we keep adding to this file?
但也许他们的家也在一个文件中 我们怎么能不断地添加到这个文件中呢？
Let me go ahead and delete the contents of students.csv
让我继续删除Students.csv的内容
and just re-add a single simple row, name, comma, home,
只需重新添加一个简单的行、名称、逗号、主页、
so as to anticipate inserting more names and homes into this file.
以便预期在此文件中插入更多的姓名和住所
And then let me go to students.py, and let me just start fresh
然后让我转到Students.py 让我重新开始
so as to write out data this time.
以便这次写出数据
I'm still going to go ahead and Import CSV.
我仍然要继续并导入CSV
I'm going to go ahead now and prompt the user for their name-- so
我现在将继续并提示用户输入他们的名字--所以
input, quote/unquote, What's your name?
输入 引用/不引用 你叫什么名字？
And I'm going to go ahead and prompt the user for their home--
接下来 我会提示用户他们的家--
so home equals input, quote/unquote, Where's your home?
所以家等于输入 引号/不引号 你的家在哪里？
Now I'm going to go ahead and open the file,
现在我要继续打开文件
but this time for writing instead of reading, as follows--
但这一次是写作而不是阅读 如下所示--
with open, quote/unquote, students.csv.
带有开放的、引用/不引用的Students.csv
I'm going to open it in append mode so that I
我要在追加模式下打开它 这样我
keep adding more and more students and homes to the file,
不断增加越来越多的学生和家庭到文件中
rather than just overwriting the entire file itself.
而不是仅仅覆盖整个文件本身
And I'm going to use a variable name of file.
我将使用变量名FILE
I'm then going to go ahead and give myself a variable called writer,
然后 我将继续为自己设置一个名为Writer的变量
and I'm going to set it equal to the return value of another function
我要将它设置为等于另一个函数的返回值
in the CSV module called csv.writer.
在名为csv.Writer的CSV模块中
And that writer function takes as its sole argument the file variable there.
而编写器函数将那里的文件变量作为其唯一参数
Now I'm going to go ahead and just do this.
现在我要继续做这件事
I'm going to say, writer.writerow, and I'm
我要说 编剧 编剧 我是
going to pass into writerow the line that I want to write to the file
要将我要写入文件的行传递给Writerow
specifically as a list.
具体地说 就是一份清单
So I'm going to give this a list of name, comma, home,
所以我要给这张名单写上名字 逗号 家
which, of course, are the contents of those variables.
当然 这就是这些变量的内容
Now I'm going to go ahead and save the file.
现在 我将继续并保存文件
I'm going to go ahead and rerun python of students.py, hit Enter.
我将继续运行python of Students.py 然后按Enter键
And what's your name?
你叫什么名字？
Well, let me go ahead and type in Harry as my name and Number Four,
好吧 让我继续输入哈里作为我的名字和数字4
comma, Privet Drive, Enter.
逗号 女贞路 回车
Now notice, that input itself did have a comma.
现在请注意 输入本身确实有一个逗号
And so if I go to my CSV file now, notice
因此 如果我现在打开我的CSV文件 请注意
that it's automatically been quoted for me so
它被自动引用给我 所以
that subsequent reads from this file don't
从该文件的后续读取不会
confuse that comma with the actual comma between Harry and his home.
把这个逗号和哈里和他家之间的实际逗号搞混了
Well, let me go ahead and run it a couple of more times.
好吧 让我继续运行它几次
Let me go ahead and rerun python of students.py.
让我继续并重新运行python of Students.py
Let me go ahead and input this time Ron and his home as The Burrow.
让我继续输入 这一次罗恩和他的家是洞穴
Let's go back to students.csv to see what it looks like.
让我们回到Students.csv看看它是什么样子
Now we see Ron, comma, The Burrow has been added automatically to the file.
现在我们看到Ron 逗号 Burrow已经被自动添加到文件中
And let's do one more--
让我们再来一次--
python of students.py, Enter.
Python of Students.py 请输入
Let's go ahead and give Draco's name and his home, which would be Malfoy Manor,
让我们继续给出德拉科的名字和他的家 那将是马尔福庄园
Enter.
进来吧
And if we go back to students.csv, now, we
如果我们回到Students.csv 现在 我们
see that Draco is in the file itself.
确保Draco在文件本身中
And the library took care of not only writing each of those rows,
而且图书馆不仅负责写每一行
per the function's name.
根据函数的名称
It also handled the escaping, so to speak, of any strings
它还处理可以说是任何字符串的转义
that themselves contained a comma, like Harry's own home.
它们包含一个逗号 就像哈利自己的家一样
Well, it turns out, there's yet another way
好吧 事实证明 还有另一种方法
we could implement this same program without having to worry about precisely
我们可以实施同样的计划 而不必担心
that order again and again and just passing in a list.
一次又一次地传递一个列表
It turns out, if we're keeping track of what's the name and what's the home,
结果是 如果我们记录下名字和家
we could use something like a dictionary to associate
我们可以用字典之类的东西
those keys with those values.
那些键和那些值
So let me go ahead and back up and remove these students from the file,
所以让我继续并备份并从文件中删除这些学生
leaving only the header row again-- name, comma, home.
再次只留下标题行-- name、逗号、home
And let me go over to students.py.
让我转到students.py
And this time, instead of using CSV writer,
这一次 我们没有使用CSV writer
I'm going to go ahead and use csv.DictWriter,
我将继续使用csv.DictWriter
which is a dictionary writer, that's going
也就是一个词典编纂者
to open the file in much the same way.
以同样的方式打开文件
But rather than write a row as this list of name,
但是 与其写一行作为这个名称列表
comma, home, what I'm now going to do is follows.
逗号 家 我现在要做的是
I'm going to first output an actual dictionary,
我将首先输出一个实际的字典
the first key of which is name, colon, and then
第一个键是name、冒号 然后
the value thereof is going to be the name that was typed in.
其值将是输入的名称
And I'm going to pass in a key of home, quote/unquote,
我将传入一个家的钥匙 引用/不引用
the value of which, of course, is the home that was typed in.
当然 它的值就是输入的房子
But with DictWriter, I do need to give it
但对于DictWriter 我确实需要给它
a hint as to the order in which those columns are when writing it out so
一个关于这些列在写出来时的顺序的提示
that, subsequently, they could be read, even if those orderings change.
即使顺序改变了 它们也可以被读取
Let me go ahead and pass in fieldnames, which
让我继续传递字段名
is a second argument to DictWriter, equals, and then
是DictWriter的第二个参数 等于 然后
a list of the actual columns that I know are
我所知道的实际列的列表
in this file, which, of course, are name, comma, home.
在这个文件中 当然 是名字 逗号 家
Those times, in quotes because that's, indeed,
那些时候 在引号里 因为这是 确实
the string names of the columns, so to speak,
列的字符串名称 可以这么说
that I intend to write to in that file.
我打算写在那个文件里
All right, now let me go ahead and go to my terminal window,
好吧 现在让我继续 去我的终端窗口
run python of students.py.
运行students.py的python
This time, I'll type in Harry's name again.
这一次 我将再次输入哈利的名字
I'll, again, type in Number Four, comma, Privet Drive, Enter.
我再输入四号逗号女贞路回车
Let's now go back to students.csv.
现在让我们回到students. csv
And voila, Harry is back in the file, and it's properly escaped or quoted.
瞧 哈利又回到了文件中 它被正确地转义或引用了
I'm sure that if we do this again with Ron and The Burrow,
我敢肯定如果我们再和罗恩和陋居合作
and let's go ahead and run it one third time with Draco and Malfoy Manor,
让我们继续第三次与德拉科和马尔福庄园合作
Enter.
进来吧
Let's go back to students.csv.
让我们回到Students.csv
And via this dictionary writer, we now have all three
通过这位词典编写者 我们现在拥有了这三个
of those students as well.
这些学生也是如此
So whereas with CSV writer, the onus is on us
因此 对于CSV编写器 责任在我们身上
to pass in a list of all of the values that we
传递我们的所有值的列表
want to put from left to right, with a dictionary writer, technically,
我想从左到右 和一个词典编写者 从技术上讲
they could be in any order in the dictionary.
它们可以在词典中以任何顺序出现
In fact, I could just have correctly done this,
事实上 我本可以正确地这么做的
passing in home followed by name.
在回家的路上 后面跟着名字
But it's a dictionary.
但这是一本词典
And so the ordering in this case does not matter so long as the key is there
因此 只要密钥在那里 这种情况下的排序就不重要了
and the value is there.
它的价值就在那里
And because I have passed in field names as the second argument to DictWriter,
由于我已将字段名作为第二个参数传递给DictWriter
it ensures that the library knows exactly which column
它确保库准确地知道哪一列
contains name or home, respectively.
分别包含名称或主页
Are there any questions now on dictionary reading, dictionary writing,
现在有没有什么关于词典阅读 词典写作
or CSVs more generally?
或者更笼统地说是CSV？
AUDIENCE: In any specific situation for me
观众：对我来说 在任何特定情况下
to use a single quotation or double quotation?
使用单引号还是双引号？
Because after the print, we use single quotation
因为在打印之后 我们使用单引号
to represent the key of the dictionary.
来表示词典的关键字
But after the reading or writing, we use the double quotation.
但在阅读或写作后 我们使用双引号
DAVID MALAN: It's a good question.
大卫·马兰：这是个好问题
In Python, you can generally use double quotes, or you can use single quotes.
在Python中 您通常可以使用双引号 也可以使用单引号
And it doesn't matter.
这都无关紧要
You should just be self-consistent so that stylistically your code
你应该保持自我一致 这样你的代码才能在风格上
looks the same all throughout.
从头到尾看起来都是一样的
Sometimes, though, it is necessary to alternate.
然而 有时交替是必要的
If you're already using double quotes, as I was earlier for a long f string,
如果您已经在使用双引号 就像我之前使用长f字符串一样
but inside that f string, I was interpolating
但在那根f弦里面 我是在插补
the values of some variables using curly braces,
一些变量的值使用大括号
and those variables were dictionaries.
这些变量都是字典
And in order to index into a dictionary, you use square brackets
为了在词典中建立索引 您可以使用方括号
and then quotes.
然后引用
But if you're already using double quotes out here,
但如果你已经在这里用双引号了
you should generally use single quotes here, or vise versa.
你通常应该在这里使用单引号 反之亦然
But otherwise, I'm in the habit of using double quotes everywhere.
但除此之外 我习惯于在任何地方使用双引号
Others are in the habit of using single quotes everywhere.
其他人则养成了到处使用单引号的习惯
It only matters sometimes if one might be confused for the other.
只有当一个人可能被混淆为另一个人时 这才是重要的
Other questions on dictionary writing or reading?
关于词典写作或阅读的其他问题？
AUDIENCE: Yeah, my question is, can we use multiple CSV files in any program?
观众：是的 我的问题是 我们可以在任何程序中使用多个CSV文件吗？
DAVID MALAN: Absolutely.
大卫·马兰：当然
You can use as many CSV files as you want.
您可以使用任意数量的CSV文件
And it's just one of the formats that you can use to save data.
这只是您可以用来保存数据的一种格式
Other questions on CSVs or File I/O?
关于CSV或文件I/O的其他问题？
AUDIENCE: Thanks for taking my question.
观众：谢谢你回答我的问题
So when you're reading from the file as a dictionary,
所以 当你把文件作为词典阅读时
you had the fields called.
你叫人给田地打了电话
When you're reading, couldn't you just call the row?
当你在看书的时候 你就不能先把它排好吗？
the previous version of the students.py file, when you're reading each row,
以前版本的Students.py文件 当您读取每行时
you were splitting out the fields by name.
你是按名字划分字段的
Yeah, so when you're appending to the students list,
是啊 所以当你加入学生名单的时候
couldn't you just call for row and reader, students.append row,
你就不能叫一下行和读者吗 学生们 追加行
rather than naming each of the fields?
而不是给每个油田命名？
DAVID MALAN: Oh, very clever.
大卫·马兰：哦 非常聪明
Short answer, yes, in so far as DictReader returns
简而言之 是的 只要DictReader返回
one dictionary at a time, when you loop over it,
一次一本词典 当你循环它的时候
row is already going to be a dictionary.
ROW已经将成为一本词典
So yes, you could actually get away with doing this.
所以 是的 你真的可以逃脱惩罚
And the effect would really be the same in this case.
在这种情况下 效果真的是一样的
Good observation.
观察得很好
How about one more question on CSVs?
再问一个关于CSV的问题如何？
AUDIENCE: Yeah, when reading in CSVs from my past work with data,
观众：是的 当我阅读我过去处理数据的CSV时
a lot of things can go wrong.
很多事情都可能出错
I don't know if it's a fair question that you can answer in a few sentences.
我不知道这是不是一个你能用几句话就能回答的问题
But are there any best practices to double check that no mistakes occurred?
但是 有没有什么最佳实践来仔细检查没有出现错误呢？
DAVID MALAN: It's a really good question.
大卫·马兰：这是一个非常好的问题
And I would say, in general, if you're using code to generate the CSVs
我会说 一般来说 如果您使用代码来生成CSV
and to read the CSVs, and you're using a good library,
为了阅读CSV 而且你使用的是一个很好的图书馆
theoretically, nothing should go wrong.
从理论上讲 应该不会出什么差错
It should be 100% correct if the libraries are 100% correct.
如果库是100%正确的 那么它应该是100%正确的
You and I tend to be the problem.
你和我往往是问题所在
When you let a human touch the CSV, or when Excel, or Apple Numbers,
当你让人触摸CSV时 或者当Excel或Apple数字时
or some other tools involved that might not
或其他一些可能不涉及的工具
be aligned with your code's expectations,
与代码的预期保持一致
things then, yes, can break.
那么 是的 事情可能会破裂
The goal-- sometimes, honestly, the solution is manual fixes.
目标是--有时候 说实话 解决方案是手动修复
You go in and fix the CSV, or you have a lot of error checking,
您可以进入并修复CSV 或者需要进行大量错误检查
or you have a lot of try, except just to tolerate mistakes in the data.
或者你有很多尝试 只是为了容忍数据中的错误
But generally, I would say, if you're using CSV or any file format
但总的来说 我想说的是 如果您使用CSV或任何文件格式
internally to a program to both read and write it,
在程序内部读取和写入它
you shouldn't have concerns there.
你不应该担心这一点
You and I, the humans, are the problem, generally
你和我 人类 通常都是问题所在
speaking-- and not the programmers, the users of those files, instead.
说话--不是程序员 而是那些文件的用户
All right, allow me to propose that we leave CSVs behind but to note
好吧 请允许我提议我们把CSV抛在脑后
that they're not the only file format you
它们不是您唯一的文件格式
can use in order to read or write data.
可以用来读写数据
In fact, they're a popular format, as is just raw text files--
事实上 它们是一种流行的格式 就像原始文本文件一样--
.txt files.
.txt文件
But you can store data, really, any way that you want.
但你可以存储数据 真的 以任何你想要的方式
We've just picked CSVs because it's representative
我们之所以选择CSV 是因为它具有代表性
of how you might read and write from a file
您可以如何从文件读取和写入
and do so in a structured way, where you can somehow have multiple keys,
并以一种结构化的方式进行操作 其中您可以以某种方式拥有多个密钥
multiple values all in the same file without having to resort to what would
多个值都在同一个文件中 而不必求助于
be otherwise known as a binary file.
也称为二进制文件
So a binary file is a file that's really just zeros and ones.
所以二进制文件实际上就是一个只有0和1的文件
And they can be laid out in any pattern you might want, particularly
它们可以按照您想要的任何图案进行布局 尤其是
if you want to store not textual information,
如果您想存储非文本信息
but maybe graphical, or audio, or video information as well.
但也可能是图形、音频或视频信息
So it turns out that Python is really good
所以事实证明 Python真的很好
when it comes to having libraries for, really, everything.
当谈到拥有所有的库时 真的 什么都有
And in fact, there's a popular library called
事实上 有一个很受欢迎的图书馆叫
pillow that allows you to navigate image files as well
枕头 让您也可以浏览图像文件
and to perform operations on image files.
以及对图像文件执行操作
You can apply filters, a la Instagram.
你可以应用滤镜 就像Instagram一样
You can animate them as well.
您也可以设置它们的动画
And so what I thought we'd do is leave behind text files for now
所以我想我们现在要做的就是留下文本文件
and tackle one more demonstration, this time,
再处理一次演示 这次
focusing on this particular library and image files instead.
而是专注于这个特定的库和图像文件
So let me propose that we go over here to VS Code
所以让我提议我们到这里来VS Code
and create a program, ultimately, that creates an animated GIF.
并创建一个程序 最终创建一个动画GIF
These things are everywhere nowadays in the form of memes, and animations,
如今 这些东西以迷因和动画的形式无处不在
and stickers, and the like.
还有贴纸之类的
And an animated GIF is really just an image file
而一个动画GIF实际上只是一个图像文件
that has multiple images inside of it.
里面有多个图像
And your computer or your phone shows you those images, one after another,
你的电脑或手机会一个接一个地向你展示这些图像
sometimes on an endless loop, again and again.
有时是无休止的循环 一次又一次
And so long as there's enough images, it creates the illusion of animation
只要有足够的图像 它就会创造出动画的错觉
because your mind and mine kind of fills in the gaps visually
因为你和我的大脑在视觉上填补了空白
and just assumes that if something is moving, even though you're only
并假设如果有什么东西在移动 即使你只是
seeing one frame per second, or some sequence thereof,
看到每秒一帧或其某个序列
it looks like an animation.
它看起来像一部动画
So it's like a simplistic version of a video file.
这就像是视频文件的简单化版本
Well, let me propose that we start with maybe a couple of costumes
好吧 让我提议我们从几件戏服开始
from another popular programming language.
来自另一种流行的编程语言
And let me go ahead and open up my first costume here, number 1.
让我继续在这里打开我的第一件戏服 1号
So suppose here that this is a costume or, really, just a static image
假设这是一件服装 或者 真的 只是一张静态图像
here, costume1.gif.
在这里 starume1.gif
And it's just a static picture of a cat, no movement at all.
这只是一只猫的静态照片 一点动作都没有
Let me go ahead now and open up a second one, costume2.gif,
现在让我们继续 打开第二个 starume2.gif
that looks a little bit different.
这看起来有点不同
Notice-- and I'll go back and forth-- this cat's legs
注意--我会来回检查--这只猫的腿
are a little bit aligned differently so that this was version 1,
有一点不同 所以这是版本1
and this was version 2.
这是第二版
Now, these cats come from a programming language from MIT
现在 这些猫来自麻省理工学院的一种编程语言
called scratch that allows you, very graphically,
称为Scratch 它允许你 非常形象地
to animate all this and more.
让这一切变得生动起来 甚至更多
But we'll use just these two static images, costume1 and costume2
但是我们将只使用这两个静态图像 分别是arcume1和stagume2
to create our own animated GIF that, after this, you
创建我们自己的动画GIF 在此之后 您
could text to a friend or message them, much like any meme online.
可以给朋友发短信或给他们发消息 就像任何在线表情包一样
Well, let me propose that we create this animated GIF, not
好吧 让我建议我们创建这个动画GIF 而不是
by just using some off-the-shelf program that we downloaded,
只要使用我们下载的一些现成的程序
but by writing our own code.
而是通过编写我们自己的代码
Let me go ahead and run code of costumes.py
让我继续运行starumes.py的代码
and create our very own program that's going to take,
并创建我们自己的项目 这将需要
as input, two or even more image files and then generate an animated GIF
作为输入 两个甚至更多的图像文件 然后生成一个动画GIF
from them by essentially creating this animated GIF by toggling back and forth
通过来回切换来创建这个动画GIF
endlessly between those two images.
在这两个图像之间没完没了地
Well, how am I going to do this?
那么 我该怎么做呢？
Well, let's assume that this will be a program called costumes.py that
好吧 让我们假设这将是一个名为staumes.py的程序
expects two command line arguments, the names
需要两个命令行参数 即名称
of the files, the individual costumes that we want to animate back and forth.
在这些文件中 我们要来回设置动画的个别服装
So to do that, I'm going to import sys so that we ultimately
要做到这一点 我将导入系统 以便我们最终
have access to sys.argv.
有权访问sys.argv
I'm then, from this pillow library, going to import support for images
然后 我将从这个枕头库导入对图像的支持
specifically.
具体地说
So from PIL import Image-- capital I, as per the library's documentation.
因此 根据图书馆的文档 从PIL导入图像--大写I
Now I'm going to give myself an empty list called images,
现在我要给自己列出一个名为图像的空列表
just so I have a list in which to store one, or two, or more of these images.
这样我就有了一个列表 可以在其中存储一张、两张或多张这样的图像
And now let me do this.
现在让我做这件事
For each argument in sys.argv, I'm going to go ahead and create a new image
对于sys.argv中的每个参数 我将继续创建一个新的映像
variable, set it equal to this Image.open function, passing in arg.
变量 将其设置为等于此Image.Open函数 传入arg
Now, what is this doing?
现在 这是在做什么？
I'm proposing that, eventually, I want to be
我建议 最终 我想成为
able to run python of costumes.py, and then
能够运行starumes.py的python 然后
as command line argument, specify costume1.gif, space, costume2.gif.
作为命令行参数 指定starume1.gif space starume2.gif
So I want to take in those file names from the command line as my arguments.
所以我想把命令行中的那些文件名作为参数
So what am I doing here?
那我在这里做什么？
Well, I'm iterating over sys.argv all of the words in my command line arguments.
我正在对sys.argv迭代我的命令行参数中的所有单词
I'm creating a variable called image, and I'm
我正在创建一个名为IMAGE的变量 我
passing to this function, Image.open from the pillow
从枕头传递给此函数Image.Open
library, that specific argument.
库 这个特定的参数
And that library is essentially going to open that image
从本质上讲 该库将打开该图像
in a way that gives me a lot of functionality for manipulating it,
在某种程度上 它给了我很多操纵它的功能
like animating.
就像动画一样
Now I'm going to go ahead and append to my images list that particular image.
现在 我将继续并将该特定图像追加到我的图像列表中
And that's it.
就是这样
So this loop's purpose in life is just to iterate over the command line
所以这个循环的目的就是在命令行上迭代
arguments and open those images using this library.
参数 并使用该库打开这些图像
The last line is pretty straightforward.
最后一行非常简单
I'm going to say this.
我要说的是
I'm going to grab the first of those images, which is going to be in my list
我将获取其中的第一张图片 它将出现在我的列表中
at location 0, and I'm going to save it to disk.
在位置0 我要将其保存到磁盘
That is, I'm going to save this file.
也就是说 我要保存这个文件
Now, in the past when we use CSVs or text files,
在过去 当我们使用CSV或文本文件时
I had to do the file opening.
我必须打开文件
I had to do the file writing, maybe even the closing.
我不得不写文件 甚至可能是结案
I don't need to do that with this library.
我不需要用这个图书馆做到这一点
The pillow library takes care of the opening, the closing, and the saving
枕头库负责打开、关闭和保存
for me by just calling save.
给我打个电话就行了
I'm going to call this save function.
我将调用此保存函数
And just to leave space, because I have a number of arguments to pass,
留个空白点 因为我有很多论点要讲
I'm going to move to another line so it fits.
我要换到另一条线 这样才合身
I'm going to pass in the name of the file that I want to create,
我将传入要创建的文件的名称
costumes.gif--
Costumes.gif--
that will be the name of my animated GIF.
这将是我的动画GIF的名字
I'm going to tell this library to save all of the frames
我要告诉这个图书馆保存所有的相框
that I pass to it-- so the first costume, the second costume, and even
所以第一套服装 第二套服装 甚至
more if I gave them.
如果我给他们更多
I'm going to then append to this first image--
然后 我将在第一张图片上添加--
the images 0-- the following images, equals this list of images.
图像0--下面的图像等于该图像列表
And this is a bit clever, but I'm going to do this.
这有点聪明 但我还是要这么做
I want to append the next image there, images[1].
我想在那里添加下一个图像 图像[1]
And now I want to specify a duration of 200 milliseconds
现在我想将持续时间指定为200毫秒
for each of these frames, and I want this to loop forever.
对于这些帧中的每一帧 我希望它永远循环
And if you specify loop=0, that is time 0,
如果您指定loop=0 也就是时间0
it means it's just not going to loop a finite number of times,
这意味着它不会循环有限次
but an infinite number of times instead.
而是无数次
And I need to do one other thing.
我还需要做另外一件事
Recall that sys.argv contains not just the words I
回想一下 sys.argv不仅包含单词i
typed after my program's name, but what else does sys.argv contain?
在我的程序名之后输入 但sys.argv还包含什么？
If you think back to our discussion of command line arguments,
如果您回想一下我们对命令行参数的讨论
what else is sys.argv besides the words I'm about to type,
除了我要输入的单词 还有什么是sys.argv
like costume1.gif and costume2?
就像starume1.gif和starume2一样？
AUDIENCE: Yeah, so we'll actually get the original name of the program
观众：是的 所以我们实际上会得到节目的原名
we want to run, the costumes.py.
我们想要运行 那就是engumes.py
DAVID MALAN: Indeed, we'll get the original name of the program,
大卫·马兰：事实上 我们会得到这个项目的原始名称
costumes.py in this case, which is not a GIF, obviously.
在本例中 这显然不是GIF
So remember that using slices in Python, we can do this.
所以请记住 在Python中使用切片 我们可以做到这一点
If sys.argv is a list, and we want to get a slice of that list, everything
如果sys.argv是一个列表 并且我们想要从该列表中分一杯羹 那么所有
after the first element, we can do 1, colon, which says,
在第一个元素之后 我们可以做1 冒号 这表示
start it location 1, not 0, and take a slice all the way to the end.
从位置1开始 而不是0 然后一直取一片到最后
So give me everything except the first thing
所以给我所有的东西 除了第一件事
in that list, which, to McKenzie's point, is the name of the program.
在这份清单中 麦肯齐认为 这就是该项目的名称
Now, if I haven't made any mistakes, let's see what happens.
现在 如果我没有犯任何错误 让我们看看会发生什么
I'm going to run python of costumes.py, and now I'm
我将运行bothon of starumes.py 现在我正在
going to specify the two images that I want to animate--
我将具体说明我想要制作动画的两个图像--
so costume1.gif and costume2.gif.
因此 starume1.gif和starume2.gif
What is the code now going to do?
代码现在要做什么？
Well, to recap, we're using the sys library
简单地说 我们使用的是sys库
to access those command line arguments.
来访问这些命令行参数
We're using the pillow library to treat those files
我们正在使用枕头库来处理这些文件
as images and with all the functionality that comes with that library.
作为图像 并具有该库附带的所有功能
I'm using this images list just to accumulate all of these images, one
我使用这个图像列表只是为了积累所有这些图像 一个
at a time from the command line.
一次从命令行执行
And in lines 7 through 9, I'm just using a loop to iterate over all of them
在第7行到第9行中 我只是使用一个循环来迭代所有它们
and just add them to this list after opening them with the library.
在图书馆打开它们后 只需将它们添加到这个列表中
And the last step, which is really just one line of code broken onto three so
最后一步 实际上只是一行代码被分成三行 所以
that it all fits, I'm going to save the first image,
这一切都符合 我要保存第一张图像
but I'm asking the library to append this other image to it
但我要求图书馆在上面附加另一张图片
as well-- not bracket 0, but bracket 1.
也一样--不是括号0 而是括号1
And if I had more, I could express those as well.
如果我有更多 我也可以表达出来
I want to save all of these files together.
我想将所有这些文件保存在一起
I want to pause 200 milliseconds-- a fifth of a second
我想暂停200毫秒--五分之一秒
in between each frame.
在每一帧之间
And I want it to loop infinitely many times.
我想让它无限循环很多次
So now if I cross my fingers as always, hit Enter,
所以现在如果我像往常一样祈祷 按回车键
nothing bad happened, and that's almost always a good thing.
没有发生什么坏事 这几乎总是一件好事
Let me now run code of costumes.gif to open up in VS Code the final image.
现在让我运行starumes.gif的代码 在VS代码中打开最终的图像
And what I think I should see is a very happy cat?
我认为我应该看到的是一只非常快乐的猫？
And indeed.
确实如此
So now we've seen not only that we can read and write files, be it textually.
所以现在我们已经看到 我们不仅可以读写文件 无论是文本文件
We can read and now write files that are binary zeros and ones.
我们现在可以读取和写入二进制0和1的文件
We've just scratched the surface.
我们只是触及了皮毛
This is using the library called pillow.
这是在使用名为Pillow的图书馆
But ultimately, this is going to give us the ability to read and write files
但最终 这将使我们能够读写文件
however we want.
随心所欲
So we've now seen that via File I/O, we can manipulate not just textual files,
我们现在已经看到 通过文件I/O 我们不仅可以操作文本文件
be it TXT files, or CSVs, but even binary files as well.
无论是TXT文件 还是CSV 甚至二进制文件也是如此
In this case, they happen to be images.
在这种情况下 它们恰好是图像
But if we dived in deeper, we could explore audio, and video,
但如果我们潜水更深 我们可以探索音频和视频
and so much more all by way of these simple primitives, this ability,
通过这些简单的原语 这种能力
somehow, to read and write files.
以某种方式读写文件
That's it for now.
这就是目前的情况
We'll see you next time.
我们下次再见